<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Series on New Directions Publishers</title>
    <link>https://example.com/series/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Series on New Directions Publishers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://example.com/series/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Christine Burgin</title>
      <link>https://example.com/series/christine-burgin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/series/christine-burgin/</guid>
      <description>With renowned gallery director Christine Burgin, New Directions presents books that are for reading, looking and touching in equal measure. The co-publications present full-color facsimile images of working drafts and new-found masterpieces. They offer never-before-possible glimpses into the process of two literary greats, Emily Dickinson and Robert Walser. Watch the shape of scrap paper guide Dickinson&amp;rsquo;s poetic pace and signature line-breaks. Discover why W.G. Sebald described Walser as a &amp;ldquo;clairvoyant of the small.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Directions Annuals</title>
      <link>https://example.com/series/new-directions-annuals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/series/new-directions-annuals/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pamphlets</title>
      <link>https://example.com/series/pamphlets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/series/pamphlets/</guid>
      <description>New Directions is happy to present a new series of Poetry Pamphlets, a reincarnated version of the &amp;ldquo;Poet of the Month&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Poets of the Year&amp;rdquo; series James Laughlin published in the 1940s, which brought out such eclectic hits as William Carlos Williams&amp;rsquo;s The Broken Span, Delmore Schwartz&amp;rsquo;s poetic play Shenandoah, John Donne&amp;rsquo;s Some Poems and Devotions, and Yvor Winters&amp;rsquo;s Giant Weapon, among many others. The New Directions Poetry Pamphlets will highlight original work by writers from around the world, as well as forgotten treasures lost in the cracks of literary history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pearls</title>
      <link>https://example.com/series/pearls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/series/pearls/</guid>
      <description>The New Directions Pearl series offers short masterpieces by great authors at enticing prices: under $10! The Pearl series presents short works from contemporary masters such as César Aira and Javier Marías, and also includes relaunches of several ND Bibelots, which introduced readers to seminal works by classic ND authors such as Borges and Mishima.
Designed by Rodrigo Corral, these slim volumes boast a striking minimalist style: bold geometric shapes against a stark white background.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>