<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on New Directions Publishers</title>
    <link>https://example.com/event/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on New Directions Publishers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 14:26:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://example.com/event/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NYC Tanizaki Launch</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/nyc-tanizaki-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 14:26:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/nyc-tanizaki-launch/</guid>
      <description>New Directions is thrilled to announce the publication of two major discoveries of works by Junichiro Tanizaki: The Maids, Tanizaki&amp;rsquo;sastonishing final novel, and Devils in Daylight, a suspenseful early novella—now in English for the first time.
To celebrate, New Directions and The Metrograph invite you to a rare screening of Kon Ichikawa&amp;rsquo;s acclaimed film adaption of The Makioka Sisters. The event will be introduced by critic and historian, Ian Buruma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tenth Muse with Anne Carson; with Mike Lala, William Levitan, and Emily Wilson</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/the-tenth-muse-with-anne-carson-with-mike-lala-william-levitan-and-emily-wilson/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 17:54:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/the-tenth-muse-with-anne-carson-with-mike-lala-william-levitan-and-emily-wilson/</guid>
      <description>Renowned as a poet and classical translator, Anne Carson continues a long-standing Poetry Center tradition by introducing readings by three of her favorite translators: Mike Lala (Catullus), William Levitan (Seneca, the letters of Abelard and Heloise) and Emily Wilson (Euripides, Homer). “You’re down in the roots of where words work,” wrote Carson of translating Greek and Latin. “In English we’re at the top of the tree, in the branches, bouncing around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Osama Alomar and C.J. Collins at The Seminary Co-op in Chicago</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/osama-alomar-and-cj-collins-at-the-seminary-co-op-in-chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/osama-alomar-and-cj-collins-at-the-seminary-co-op-in-chicago/</guid>
      <description>Osama Alomar and his translator, C.J. Collins, will discuss the translation process, the stories in The Teeth of the Comb, and read in both English and Arabic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thomas Merton and Robert Lax Exhibition at St. Bonaventure Institute, NY</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/thomas-merton-and-robert-lax-exhibition-at-st-bonaventure-institute-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 19:06:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/thomas-merton-and-robert-lax-exhibition-at-st-bonaventure-institute-ny/</guid>
      <description>Thomas Merton (1915 – 1968) was a Catholic writer, theologian and mystic. A Trappist monk of the Abbey of Gethsemani, Kentucky, he was a poet, social activist, and student of comparative religion. He wrote more than 70 books, mostly on spirituality, social justice and pacifism, as well as scores of essays and reviews. His bestselling autobiography, &amp;ldquo;The Seven Storey Mountain (1948),&amp;rdquo; was selected by National Review as one of the 100 best non-fiction books of the 20th century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nathaniel Mackey reading in Amherst</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/nathaniel-mackey-reading-in-amherst/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 18:54:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/nathaniel-mackey-reading-in-amherst/</guid>
      <description>Nathaniel Mackey is an award-winning poet, novelist, editor and critic. He is the author of numerous books of poetry, including Nod House (2011), the National Book Award-winning Splay Anthem (2006) and Eroding Witness (1985), which was chosen for the National Poetry Series. He has published several book-length installments of his ongoing prose work, From a Broken Bottle Traces of Perfume Still Emanate, beginning with Bedouin Hornbook in 1986. A New York Times review described the prose project as “not simply writing about jazz, but writing as jazz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Osama Alomar at Focus On Syria at Loyola University, Chicago</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/osama-alomar-at-focus-on-syria-at-loyola-university-chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 18:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/osama-alomar-at-focus-on-syria-at-loyola-university-chicago/</guid>
      <description>During Focus on Syria, author Osama Alomar will read from his book The Teeth of the Comb and talk about the Syrian political situation with playwright, director, and former Syrian minister Riad Ismat; and Northwestern political science professor Wendy Pearlman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Little Buddhist Monk &amp; The Proof: César Aira &amp; Heather Cleary at McNally Jakcson</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/the-little-buddhist-monk-the-proof-c-sar-aira-heather-cleary-at-mcnally-jakcson/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 18:22:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/the-little-buddhist-monk-the-proof-c-sar-aira-heather-cleary-at-mcnally-jakcson/</guid>
      <description>Two completely different novellas by the inimitable César Aira. The Little Buddhist Monk is a story of Asian invention gone wild, as a diminutive Korean Buddhist monk acts as a tour guide to an increasingly distraught French couple on a working vacation in the Far East. The Proof brings us quickly back to the West, where two punks, plus a new recruit, take control of a local supermarket with dire consequences for the hostages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Translation Deep Dive: Gozo and the Sea of Translators&#34; with Gozo Yoshimasu, Forrest Gander, Sawako Nakayasu, and Kyoko Yoshida, Iowa city</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/translation-deep-dive-gozo-and-the-sea-of-translators-with-gozo-yoshimasu-forrest-gander-sawako-nakayasu-and-kyoko-yoshida-iowa-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 16:12:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/translation-deep-dive-gozo-and-the-sea-of-translators-with-gozo-yoshimasu-forrest-gander-sawako-nakayasu-and-kyoko-yoshida-iowa-city/</guid>
      <description>A Half Century of Writers in Iowa: Writing and Translating at the International Writing Program, 1967-2017
A translation workshop sponsored by Exchanges, with Gozo Yoshimasu, Forrest Gander, Sawako Nakayasu, and Kyoko Yoshida.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gozo Yoshimasu &amp; Forrest Gander at &#34;How Literature Travels: Translators Between Languages&#34;, Iowa City</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/gozo-yoshimasu-forrest-gander-at-how-literature-travels-translators-between-languages-iowa-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 16:02:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/gozo-yoshimasu-forrest-gander-at-how-literature-travels-translators-between-languages-iowa-city/</guid>
      <description>A Half Century of Writers in Iowa: Writing and Translating at the International Writing Program, 1967-2017
A translation workshop with Gozo Yoshimasu, Forrest Gander, Kyoko Yoshida, Nori Nakagami, and Anne McKnight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Gozo: The Medium is the Messenger&#34; Gozo Yoshimasu, Forrest Gander, Sawako Nakayasu, and Kyoko Yoshida, Iowa City</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/gozo-the-medium-is-the-messenger-gozo-yoshimasu-forrest-gander-sawako-nakayasu-and-kyoko-yoshida-iowa-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 15:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/gozo-the-medium-is-the-messenger-gozo-yoshimasu-forrest-gander-sawako-nakayasu-and-kyoko-yoshida-iowa-city/</guid>
      <description>A Half Century of Writers in Iowa: Writing and Translating at the International Writing Program, 1967-2017
A poetry and multimedia performance with Gozo Yoshimasu, Forrest Gander, Sawako Nakayasu, and Kyoko Yoshida, featuring the Laptop Orchestra with Professor Jean-François Charles, conductor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gozo Yoshimasu at Prairie Lights, Iowa City</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/gozo-yoshimasu-at-prairie-lights-iowa-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 15:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/gozo-yoshimasu-at-prairie-lights-iowa-city/</guid>
      <description>A Half Century of Writers in Iowa: Writing and Translating at the International Writing Program, 1967-2017
Gozo Yoshimasu will read from his collection, Alice Iris Red Horse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading by Nathaniel Mackey and John Keene at Williams College, MA</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/reading-by-nathaniel-mackey-and-john-keene-at-williams-college-ma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 19:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/reading-by-nathaniel-mackey-and-john-keene-at-williams-college-ma/</guid>
      <description>Nathaniel Mackey and John Keene come together for a reading at Williams College in Williamstown, MA.
Nathaniel Mackey is an American poet, novelist, anthologist, literary critic and editor. He is the Reynolds Price Professor of Creative Writing at Duke University and a Chancellor of The Academy of American Poets. John R. Keene Jr. is a writer, translator, professor, and artist. Formerly associate professor of English and African American studies at Northwestern University, Illinois, United States, he now is Associate Professor of English, chairs the African American and African Studies department, and teaches in the MFA in Creative Program at Rutgers University-Newark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nathaniel Mackey and Claudia Rankine receive the Bobbitt National Prize for Poetry and read selections from their work in D.C.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/nathaniel-mackey-and-claudia-rankine-receive-the-bobbitt-national-prize-for-poetry-and-read-selections-from-their-work-in-dc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 18:35:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/nathaniel-mackey-and-claudia-rankine-receive-the-bobbitt-national-prize-for-poetry-and-read-selections-from-their-work-in-dc/</guid>
      <description>The Library of Congress will present the 2016 Rebekah Johnson Bobbitt National Prize for Poetry to Claudia Rankine, for her book “Citizen: An American Lyric,” and to Nathaniel Mackey, for lifetime achievement.
Rankine and Mackey will receive the awards and read selections from their work at 6:30 p.m. on Thursday, April 20, in the Montpelier Room on the sixth floor of the James Madison Building. The reading is free and open to the public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Osama Alomar at Pittsburgh Humanities Festival</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/osama-alomar-at-pittsburgh-humanities-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 17:57:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/osama-alomar-at-pittsburgh-humanities-festival/</guid>
      <description>Born in Damascus, Syria in 1968 and now living in Pittsburgh, Osama Alomar is the author of three collections of short stories and a volume of poetry. He is a regular contributor to various newspapers and journals within the Arab world.
Osama Alomar will be interviewed by Ross Harrison, faculty member at the School of Foreign Service at Georgetown University and scholar at The Middle East Institute in Washington, DC. He also teaches a course in Middle East politics at the University of Pittsburgh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Offbeat operas&#34; by Frank Brickle/Ezra Pound, William Anderson/Djuna Barnes and Victoria Bond/James Joyce at Cutting Edge Concerts New Music Festival 2017, Symphony Space</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/offbeat-operas-by-frank-brickleezra-pound-william-andersondjuna-barnes-and-victoria-bondjames-joyce-at-cutting-edge-concerts-new-music-festival-2017-symphony-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 17:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/offbeat-operas-by-frank-brickleezra-pound-william-andersondjuna-barnes-and-victoria-bondjames-joyce-at-cutting-edge-concerts-new-music-festival-2017-symphony-space/</guid>
      <description>The final concert of the 2017 Cutting Edge Concerts New Music Festival features the Cygnus Ensemble in a program of &amp;ldquo;Offbeat Operas&amp;rdquo; by composers William Anderson, Frank Brickle, and the world premiere of Victoria Bond&amp;rsquo;s Sirens.
William Anderson&amp;rsquo;s Eight Rhythms, Settings is based on a set of poems by Djuna Barnes from 1915. Anderson&amp;rsquo;s utilizes many kinds of contemporary idioms&amp;ndash; indie rock, Simon &amp;amp; Garfunkel, and a bit of minimalism as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Esther Allen, Katrina Dodson, Katrine Øgaard Jensen and Eli K. P. William at US&amp;Them at Molasses books</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/esther-allen-katrina-dodson-katrine--gaard-jensen-and-eli-k-p-william-at-usthem-at-molasses-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 15:49:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/esther-allen-katrina-dodson-katrine--gaard-jensen-and-eli-k-p-william-at-usthem-at-molasses-books/</guid>
      <description>Us&amp;amp;Them gives literary translators with parallel careers as writers a place to showcase both sides of their work. Readings are hosted four times a year at Molasses Books in Bushwick.
Esther Allen and Katrina Dodson will be sharing the Us&amp;amp;Them spotlight on Friday 4&amp;frasl;28 at Molasses Books with Danish translator Katrine Jensen and Japanese sci-fi translator Eli K.P. William.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/ezk8fc-7pdiPQdwf-2XXyj8DuVjYVXXD_FpchFjJdddMe1XjVtfYCkcYjzJls8nkWUjWikg6Qe3O5TzzvE_wW3tnFNYZ=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1490197723387/usthem.jpg) Esther Allen (1962– ) has translated Javier Marias, Jorge Luis Borges, Felisberto Hernandez, Flaubert, Rosario Castellanos, Blaise Cendrars, Marie Darrieussecq, and Jose Marti.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Reading and Conversation with Rachel Kushner at Purchase College</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/a-reading-and-conversation-with-rachel-kushner-at-purchase-college/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 16:08:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/a-reading-and-conversation-with-rachel-kushner-at-purchase-college/</guid>
      <description>Rachel Kushner is the author of two novels, Telex from Cuba (2008) and The Flamethrowers (2013), as well as a collection of short stories, The Strange Case of Rachel K (2015). She was awarded a Guggenheim Fellowship in 2013.
“I’m thrilled that Rachel Kushner is coming to Purchase as part of our incredible Durst Distinguished Lecture Series this year. It’s exciting for our students to be able to interact with her and her work,” says Kathleen McCormick, Purchase College professor of literature and pedagogy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guts with Katrina Dodson and Anna Joy Springer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/guts-with-katrina-dodson-and-anna-joy-springer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 20:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/guts-with-katrina-dodson-and-anna-joy-springer/</guid>
      <description>ABOUT THIS SHOW
GUTS is a bare-bones reading series which encourages experimentation. Writers from a wide variety of styles and life phases are invited to read new work and discuss their practices in an intimate setting. Curated by Dia Felix.
ABOUT THE AUTHORS
KATRINA DODSON is the translator of Clarice Lispector’s Complete Stories, winner of the the 2016 PEN Translation Prize and other awards. She is currently translating the Brazilian modernist classic Macunaíma: the Hero Without a Character for New Directions and adapting her Lispector translation journal into a book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NBCC Awards Ceremony with Bernadette Mayer at the New School</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/nbcc-awards-ceremony-with-bernadette-mayer-at-the-new-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 17:35:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/nbcc-awards-ceremony-with-bernadette-mayer-at-the-new-school/</guid>
      <description>Every year, the National Book Critics Circle presents awards for the finest books published in English in the categories of Fiction, General Nonfiction, Biography, Autobiography, Poetry, and Criticism. On Wednesday, March 15, finalists will read from their work and awards will be presented on Thursday, March 16.
Here is the complete list of NBCC Award finalists for the publishing year 2016:
AUTOBIOGRAPHY
Marion Coutts, The Iceberg (Black Cat Press)
Jenny Diski, In Gratitude (Bloomsbury)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NBCC Finalists reading with Bernadette Mayer at the New School</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/nbcc-finalists-reading-with-bernadette-mayer-at-the-new-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 17:31:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/nbcc-finalists-reading-with-bernadette-mayer-at-the-new-school/</guid>
      <description>Every year, the National Book Critics Circle presents awards for the finest books published in English in the categories of Fiction, General Nonfiction, Biography, Autobiography, Poetry, and Criticism. On Wednesday, March 15, finalists will read from their work and awards will be presented on Thursday, March 16.
Here is the complete list of NBCC Award finalists for the publishing year 2016:
AUTOBIOGRAPHY
Marion Coutts, The Iceberg (Black Cat Press)
Jenny Diski, In Gratitude (Bloomsbury)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jeffrey Yang and Robyn Creswell at Community Bookstore</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/jeffrey-yang-and-robyn-creswell-at-community-bookstore/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 17:22:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/jeffrey-yang-and-robyn-creswell-at-community-bookstore/</guid>
      <description>Jeffrey Yang and Robyn Creswell join Community Bookstore to discuss two important books they translated for New Directions. Open Up, City Gate (Yang) is Bei Dao’s lyrical autobiography&amp;ndash;a beautiful memory palace of endless alleyways and corridors&amp;ndash;where personal narrative mixes with China’s momentous history. Abdelfattah Kilito’s The Tongue of Adam (Creswell) considers the genesis of multilingualism through the historical debates on the language of the first man: Adam.
Jeffrey Yang is the author of the poetry collections Vanishing-Line and An Aquarium, winner of the PEN/Joyce Osterweil Award.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carson McCullers&#39; The Member of the Wedding, A Book Discussion in Charlotte, NC</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/carson-mccullers-the-member-of-the-wedding-a-book-discussion-in-charlotte-nc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 17:19:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/carson-mccullers-the-member-of-the-wedding-a-book-discussion-in-charlotte-nc/</guid>
      <description>Part of Charlotte Lit&amp;rsquo;s Year-Long Celebration of Carson McCullers 100th Anniversary:
The Member of the Wedding, a book discussion with Kathie Collins. Registration required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 Frost Medalist Susan House at 107th Annual Poetry Society of America Awards Ceremony</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/2017-frost-medalist-susan-house-at-107th-annual-poetry-society-of-america-awards-ceremony/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 15:48:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/2017-frost-medalist-susan-house-at-107th-annual-poetry-society-of-america-awards-ceremony/</guid>
      <description>An evening honoring 2017 Frost Medalist Susan Howe – who will deliver the annual Frost Lecture – and celebrating the winners of the other Annual Awards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Osama Alomar and Riad Ismat at Voices of Protest, a Chicago City of Refuge Event: On Syria</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/osama-alomar-and-riad-ismat-at-voices-of-protest-a-chicago-city-of-refuge-event-on-syria/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 20:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/osama-alomar-and-riad-ismat-at-voices-of-protest-a-chicago-city-of-refuge-event-on-syria/</guid>
      <description>In collaboration with International Cities of Refuge Network (ICORN) and PEN International, the Chicago Network for Justice and Peace, the Guild Literary Complex returns with a second CHICAGO CITY OF REFUGE event highlighting the plight of exiled writers in Chicago as we champion the freedom of speech.
This April 9th join the conversation moderated by Wendy Pearlman highlighting the work of renowned Syrian playwright Riad Ismat, and author/poet Osama Alomar at special event as we discuss the complex plight of Syria and the Syrian refugee crisis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Culture&#39;s ND Section Party! </title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/book-cultures-nd-section-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 17:03:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/book-cultures-nd-section-party/</guid>
      <description>We are thrilled that a section of New Directions&amp;rsquo;s best fiction and poetry titles is now featured at Book Culture. Please join us for drinks, nibbles, and micro readings of favorite ND poems from special guests (to be announced).
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/ytKWhp06oKV59jFkRMQYqdRhHae9hGOyKyKAy5WTB9-nBh8JsZz6TiFXOdUPfec3VbL6TS_k7dFqqJGgXzkHVA3HQ48=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1488906049782/Screen%20Shot%202017-03-07%20at%2011.07.31%20AM.png) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nathaniel Mackey &amp; Henry Grimes at McNally Jackson</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/nathaniel-mackey-henry-grimes-at-mcnally-jackson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 22:35:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/nathaniel-mackey-henry-grimes-at-mcnally-jackson/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/MzjRajRuSPFyy1x4iFeONTtlR1_DOLD3RQUDwSZPoc8-DLdZZ7l26HT8G_5fVM_nBeYNF_9r9KXl1U_QmOrmMIOW7Nbl=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1488839290991/2016-04-21%2017.33.53.jpg) Nathaniel Mackey and Henry Grimes at the Whitney Museum, 2016  To celebrate the launch of Late Arcade, the latest volume of Nathaniel Mackey&amp;rsquo;s ongoing jazz novel, New Directions and McNally Jackson invite you to an evening of reading and music with Mackey and the great jazz musician Henry Grimes.
&amp;ldquo;A literary adventure of the highest order, a feat of prose and imagination that takes the fiction genre into new territory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selected Shorts: The Stories of Carson McCullers </title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/selected-shorts-the-stories-of-carson-mccullers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 17:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/selected-shorts-the-stories-of-carson-mccullers/</guid>
      <description>Tim Gunn (Project Runway), Hilton Als (White Girls) and more celebrate Carson McCullers, the renowned Southern Gothic author of The Heart Is a Lonely Hunter and The Member of the Wedding, whose writing explores the tragicomedy of life in the South and the inner lives of characters who are often marginalized and misunderstood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Screening of &#34;This is My Letter to the World&#34; documentary about Emily Dickinson at Morgan Museum and Library</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/screening-of-this-is-my-letter-to-the-world-documentary-about-emily-dickinson-at-morgan-museum-and-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 17:08:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/screening-of-this-is-my-letter-to-the-world-documentary-about-emily-dickinson-at-morgan-museum-and-library/</guid>
      <description>More details to follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Screening of Emily Dickinson biopic &#39;A Quiet Passion&#39; and Q&amp;A with director Terence Davies at Morgan Museum and Library</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/screening-of-emily-dickinson-biopic-a-quiet-passion-and-qa-with-director-terence-davies-at-morgan-museum-and-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 17:04:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/screening-of-emily-dickinson-biopic-a-quiet-passion-and-qa-with-director-terence-davies-at-morgan-museum-and-library/</guid>
      <description>Cynthia Nixon delivers a triumphant performance as Emily Dickinson as she personifies the wit, intellectual independence and pathos of the poet whose genius only came to be recognized after her death. Acclaimed British director Terence Davies (THE DEEP BLUE SEA, HOUSE OF MIRTH, THE LONG DAY CLOSES) exquisitely evokes Dickinson’s deep attachment to her close knit family along with the manners, mores and spiritual convictions of her time that she struggled with and transcended in her poetry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoko Tawada reading and panel discussion at Oxford University</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/yoko-tawada-reading-and-panel-discussion-at-oxford-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 17:02:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/yoko-tawada-reading-and-panel-discussion-at-oxford-university/</guid>
      <description>This event will consist of a multilingual reading (German and Japanese with English translations) and panel discussion on &amp;lsquo;Poetics of Translation&amp;rsquo; (chair: Matthew Reynolds). All welcome.
Dr Yoko Tawada will also give a German reading, followed by Q&amp;amp;A session on Wednesday 22 February, 5:30pm, at the Taylor Institution Library (Room 2), chaired by Christoph Held.
In addition to the two public readings, the Taylorian will host an exhibition on her work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tennessee Williams&#39; Paintings on Display in St. Louis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/tennessee-williams-paintings-on-display-in-st-louis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 15:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/tennessee-williams-paintings-on-display-in-st-louis/</guid>
      <description>The remarkable showcase, Tennessee Williams: The Playwright and the Painter, is a major coup for St. Louis. These 18 deeply personal paintings, only once before shown outside of Key West, illustrate how Williams&amp;rsquo; magical poetry brilliantly suffuses every art form he undertakes. Exhibited at the St. Louis University Museum of Art, they are on loan from the Key West Art &amp;amp; Historical Society and the owner of the paintings, Williams’s longtime friend David Wolkowsky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Che Malambo | On Stage at Kingsborough</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/che-malambo-on-stage-at-kingsborough/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 18:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/che-malambo-on-stage-at-kingsborough/</guid>
      <description>“A thrilling display of malambo that doesn’t come around New York too often.” - The New York Times
In a thrilling spectacle of percussive dance and music, Che Malambo brings awe-inspiring precision footwork, rhythmic stomping, drumming, singing, and whirling boleadoras (lassos) to our stage. Danced solely by men, the fiery malambo tradition began in the 17th century as competitive duels that would challenge skills of agility, strength, and zapeteo, the fast-paced footwork inspired by the rhythm of the galloping horses of their native Argentina.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Translating Clarice Lispector | Katrina Dodson at Columbia University</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/on-translating-clarice-lispector-katrina-dodson-at-columbia-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 18:32:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/on-translating-clarice-lispector-katrina-dodson-at-columbia-university/</guid>
      <description>The monumental Complete Stories of Clarice Lispector in Katrina Dodson’s much-lauded translation exploded on the U.S. literary scene in 2015. Dodson will speak about the Lispector phenomenon and the joys and challenges of translating her work in conversation with Susan Bernofsky, Director of Literary Translation at Columbia, and Minna Proctor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Clarice Factor | A Lispector Conference at Columbia University</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/the-clarice-factor-a-lispector-conference-at-columbia-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 18:16:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/the-clarice-factor-a-lispector-conference-at-columbia-university/</guid>
      <description>Katrina Dodson, translator of The Complete Stories, will speak at a two-day conference on aesthetics, gender, &amp;amp; diaspora in Brazil &amp;ndash; seen through a Lispectorian frame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rediscovering Clarice Lispector at UC Berkeley</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/rediscovering-clarice-lispector-at-uc-berkeley/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 17:04:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/rediscovering-clarice-lispector-at-uc-berkeley/</guid>
      <description>The 2015 publication of The Complete Stories, by Clarice Lispector, set off a global wave of appreciation for the Brazilian icon. Translator Katrina Dodson discusses the phenomenon of &amp;ldquo;Lispectormania&amp;rdquo; and the pleasures and challenges of translating a lifetime of stories marked by echoes of mysticism, explorations of women&amp;rsquo;s everyday lives, and Lispector’s often-puzzling use of Portugue</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patti Smith, Jesse Smith, Ani DiFranco, Marlon James, Colum McCann, and Salman Rushdie at PEN&#39;s World Voices event: United Against Hate</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/patti-smith-jesse-smith-ani-difranco-marlon-james-colum-mccann-and-salman-rushdie-at-pens-world-voices-event-united-against-hate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 03:41:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/patti-smith-jesse-smith-ani-difranco-marlon-james-colum-mccann-and-salman-rushdie-at-pens-world-voices-event-united-against-hate/</guid>
      <description>Voices in the arts rally against hate, with performances, readings, and conversations from Patti Smith with her daughter Jesse Smith, Ani DiFranco, Marlon James, Colum McCann, Adonis, and Salman Rushdie.
Founded in the aftermath of September 11, 2001, by Salman Rushdie, Esther Allen, and Michael Roberts with the aim of broadening channels of dialogue between the U.S. and the world, PEN World Voices is the only international literary festival in America, and the only one in the world with a human rights focus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Susan Bernofsky, John Keene and Rivka Galchen on Translation at the Margins | Festival Neue Literatur</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/susan-bernofsky-john-keene-and-rivka-galchen-on-translation-at-the-margins-festival-neue-literatur/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 23:47:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/susan-bernofsky-john-keene-and-rivka-galchen-on-translation-at-the-margins-festival-neue-literatur/</guid>
      <description>Join Festival Neue Literatur for an intimate conversation about literature in translation with NYC’s celebrated literary editors, translators, and writers, who will discuss the importance of translating the voices of marginalized writers including LGBTQ individuals, people of color and women, as well as voices of writers from countries affected by the U.S. immigration ban. Featuring: Susan Bernofsky, Rivka Galchen, John Keene, Sara Khalili, and more. Moderated by translator and Guggenheim Fellow Tess Lewis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patti Smith: In Her Own Words, at Sydney Opera House</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/patti-smith-in-her-own-words-at-sydney-opera-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 22:09:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/patti-smith-in-her-own-words-at-sydney-opera-house/</guid>
      <description>In a rare solo appearance Patti Smith will take to the stage of the Joan Sutherland Theatre as part of the Sydney Opera House Talks &amp;amp; Ideas program – to talk, read and sing from her acclaimed body of work.
Smith will discuss the many and varied dimensions of a career that spans thirteen studio albums, visual arts, poetry, a memoir and fiction.
In 2005, Patti Smith received the Commandeur de l&amp;rsquo;Ordre des Arts et des Lettres, the highest honour awarded by the French Republic to eminent artists and writers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading and Conversation with John Keene at NYU</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/reading-and-conversation-with-john-keene-at-nyu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 22:04:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/reading-and-conversation-with-john-keene-at-nyu/</guid>
      <description>Join us for a reading and discussion of John Keene&amp;rsquo;s acclaimed novel, Counternarratives. The book is a collection of novellas and stories that offers new perspectives on familiar characters and histories — ranging from Huckleberry Finn and Langston Hughes to the American Revolution and early colonial South America — as inspired by real events and records. Panelists discuss the book&amp;rsquo;s unique format and its political and historical commentary.
Panelists include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Classic? Arabic and the Horizons of Translation — Robyn Creswell, Elias Muhanna and Peter Cole at NYU</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/what-is-a-classic-arabic-and-the-horizons-of-translation-robyn-creswell-elias-muhanna-and-peter-cole-at-nyu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 21:34:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/what-is-a-classic-arabic-and-the-horizons-of-translation-robyn-creswell-elias-muhanna-and-peter-cole-at-nyu/</guid>
      <description>A panel discussion with Robyn Creswell (Comparative Literature, Yale), Elias Muhanna (Comparative Literature, Brown), and Peter Cole (Poet and Translator)
The rich corpus of Classical Arabic literature, encompassing poetry, history, science, and theology, is only beginning to be translated into English. What special obstacles do these texts pose for translators, and how might they speak to contemporary concerns with comparative philology, secular traditions within Islam, and the specter of untranslatability? Shihab al-Din al-Nuwayri’s 14th-century encyclopedia, The Ultimate Ambition in the Arts of Erudition, is a compendium of historical knowledge, literary craft, and scientific lore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idra Novey reading at PEN World Voices Festival Literary Quest, Westbeth Edition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/idra-novey-reading-at-pen-world-voices-festival-literary-quest-westbeth-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 16:09:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/idra-novey-reading-at-pen-world-voices-festival-literary-quest-westbeth-edition/</guid>
      <description>Literary Quest: Westbeth Edition
Westbeth residents will open their homes for readings by authors and a party in their legendary gallery.
Idra Novey, translator of The Passion According to G.H., will read from her novel Ways to Disappear. Also reading are: Moustafa Bayoumi, Giannina Braschi (Puerto Rico), Rita Mae Brown (US),Oddný Eir (Iceland), Farah Jasmine Griffin (US), Abeer Hoque (Nigeria/Bangladesh/American), Thomas Meinecke (Germany/US), Haroon Moghul, Tanwi Nandini Islam, Mayra Santos-Febres (Puerto Rico),Igor Stiks (UK), Han Yujoo (Korea), Filip Springer (Poland), Gabby Rivera (US) and Emanuel Xavier (US).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Keene reading at Brown University</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/john-keene-reading-at-brown-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 20:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/john-keene-reading-at-brown-university/</guid>
      <description>John Keene reads from Counternarratives at Brown University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rivka Galchen reading at Wilkes University</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/rivka-galchen-reading-at-wilkes-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 20:37:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/rivka-galchen-reading-at-wilkes-university/</guid>
      <description>Rivka Galchen opens Wilkes University’s Allan Hamilton Dickson Spring Writers Series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selected Shorts: A Celebration of Clarice Lispector at Symphony Space</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/selected-shorts-a-celebration-of-clarice-lispector-at-symphony-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 21:06:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/selected-shorts-a-celebration-of-clarice-lispector-at-symphony-space/</guid>
      <description>Host Denis O&amp;rsquo;Hare (American Horror Story), Lynn Cohen (Sex and the City), Carolina Ravassa (The Affair), and more perform stories by one of Brazil&amp;rsquo;s greatest modern writers. With commentary by novelist and translator Idra Novey (Ways to Disappear).
A cultural icon in Brazil, her work has only recently come to light in the States thanks to an award-winning translation published by New Directions. Arresting, magnetic and remarkable, her stories blend the mundane and the mystical, leaving readers unsettled somewhere in between.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bernadette Mayer: An Evening of Poetry at Time and Space, Hudson, NY</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/bernadette-mayer-an-evening-of-poetry-at-time-and-space-hudson-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 21:54:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/bernadette-mayer-an-evening-of-poetry-at-time-and-space-hudson-ny/</guid>
      <description>Bernadette Mayer is an avant-garde writer associated with the New York School of poets. Her newest collection, Works and Days (2016), is a finalist for the National Book Critics Circle award. Bernadette’s poetry often challenges poetic conventions by experimenting with form and stream-of-consciousness. Readers have compared her to Gertrude Stein, Dadaist writers, and James Joyce. She has taught at the New School for Social Research and The Poetry Project at St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Osama Alomar and Unomah Azuah at launch of Chicago City of Refuge project for exhiled writers</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/osama-alomar-and-unomah-azuah-at-launch-of-chicago-city-of-refuge-project-for-exhiled-writers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 18:57:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/osama-alomar-and-unomah-azuah-at-launch-of-chicago-city-of-refuge-project-for-exhiled-writers/</guid>
      <description>In collaboration with International Cities of Refuge Network (ICORN) and PEN International, the Chicago Network for Justice and Peace and the Guild Literary Complex announce the launch of the CHICAGO CITY OF REFUGE project for exiled writers.
Exiled writers are forced from their homelands because of persecutions and imprisonments, threatened with torture or death. Living in extreme jeopardy for the nonviolent expression of their opinions and the practice of their art, they have chosen to make Chicago their new home where they can live, work, and write in freedom and dignity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lydia Davis and Eliot Weinberger at Fort Gansevoort</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/lydia-davis-and-eliot-weinberger-at-fort-gansevoort/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 14:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/lydia-davis-and-eliot-weinberger-at-fort-gansevoort/</guid>
      <description>Lydia Davis reads from her forthcoming translation of Marcel Proust&amp;rsquo;s Letters to His Neighbor; and Eliot Weinberger reads from his new book, The Ghosts of Birds.
New Books from New Directions: 3 Celebrations is co-hosted by Fort Gansevoort Gallery, now showing New Work by Alan Cote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Directions Poets / Bryant Park Winter Reading Series: Mei-Mei Bersenbrugge, Thalia Field, Susan Howe, Michael Palmer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/new-directions-poets-bryant-park-winter-reading-series-mei-mei-bersenbrugge-thalia-field-susan-howe-michael-palmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 19:01:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/new-directions-poets-bryant-park-winter-reading-series-mei-mei-bersenbrugge-thalia-field-susan-howe-michael-palmer/</guid>
      <description>Please join New Directions and the Bryant Park Reading Room Winter Poetry series for a program of ND poets of distinction. With readings by Mei-mei Berssenbrugge, Thalia Field, Susan Howe, and Michael Palmer.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/a52MnUuoBgkl6gNx0GD8lT9L1B37lRIVQKYsV-EBl8WbjYOvpwh1US-PbQtC_Nw36RTFvGB-xtmDXpaBsKSGvVQBuCVA=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1486147875939/IMG_0669.JPG) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Keene at NMSU’s Black History Month</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/john-keene-at-nmsus-black-history-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 23:13:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/john-keene-at-nmsus-black-history-month/</guid>
      <description>John Keene will speak at New Mexico State University as part of Black History Month activities in February. Rutgers Associate Professor and Chair of African-American and African Studies, Keene recently published a book titled “Counternarratives,” a collection of fictional stories, with New Directions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hilton Als lecture on Carson McCullers in Columbus, GA</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/hilton-als-lecture-on-carson-mccullers-in-columbus-ga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 20:32:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/hilton-als-lecture-on-carson-mccullers-in-columbus-ga/</guid>
      <description>Hilton Als will be a keynote speaker in the citywide celebration “Carson at 100: The McCullers Centennial,” marking the 100th anniversary of her birth in Columbus. The events are a joint effort by CVL and the Columbus State University Carson McCullers Center for Writers and Musicians, headquartered in her childhood home, 1519 Stark Ave.
Wunderkind. Respected. Venerated. Scandalous. Misunderstood. With her debut novel, Columbus-born and bred Carson McCullers burst onto the scene at the ripe old age of 23 and helped change the course of Southern (and American) literature forever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Susan Howe and Marta Werner on Emily Dickinson&#39;s manuscripts at the Morgan Library &amp; Museum</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/susan-howe-and-marta-werner-on-emily-dickinsons-manuscripts-at-the-morgan-library-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 18:04:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/susan-howe-and-marta-werner-on-emily-dickinsons-manuscripts-at-the-morgan-library-museum/</guid>
      <description>Join poet and essayist Susan Howe and Marta Werner, professor of English at D’Youville College, for an evening of lecture and discussion centered on Emily Dickinson’s unique manuscript practice. Howe and Werner will chart the visual and sonic topographies of Dickinson’s poetry and letters, while also raising questions about writing, the limits of privacy, and the indecipherable nature of final intentions. Audience members are encouraged to be active participants in the conversation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I’m Nobody! Who are you? The Life and Poetry of Emily Dickinson at the Morgan Museum and Library</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/im-nobody-who-are-you-the-life-and-poetry-of-emily-dickinson-at-the-morgan-museum-and-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 18:02:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/im-nobody-who-are-you-the-life-and-poetry-of-emily-dickinson-at-the-morgan-museum-and-library/</guid>
      <description>One of the most popular and enigmatic American writers of the nineteenth century, Emily Dickinson (1830–1886) wrote almost 1,800 poems. Nevertheless, her work was essentially unknown to contemporary readers since only a handful of poems were published during her lifetime and a vast trove of her manuscripts was not discovered until after her death in 1886.
Often typecast as a recluse who rarely left her Amherst home, Dickinson was, in fact, socially active as a young woman and maintained a broad network of friends and correspondents even as she grew older and retreated into seclusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk on Denise Levertov in Belmont Public Library, MA</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/talk-on-denise-levertov-in-belmont-public-library-ma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 17:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/talk-on-denise-levertov-in-belmont-public-library-ma/</guid>
      <description>In the Assembly Room of the Belmont Public Library, librarian Miriam MacNair will discuss the life and work of poet Denise Levertov, focusing on The Collected Poems of Denise Levertov and on two biographies, Denise Levertov: A Poet&amp;rsquo;s Life by Dana Greene and A Poet&amp;rsquo;s Revolution: The Life of Denise Levertov by Donna Krolik Hollenberg. Born in England in 1923, Levertov emigrated in 1948 to the United States. She published her first book of poetry in England at the age of 23, but it was not until she moved to the United States that she found her poetic voice, helped by poets William Carlos Williams, Robert Duncan and Robert Creeley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bernadette Mayer reading at the University of Denver</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/bernadette-mayer-reading-at-the-university-of-denver/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 19:42:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/bernadette-mayer-reading-at-the-university-of-denver/</guid>
      <description>The University of Denver is pleased to announce that Bernadette Mayer, a finalist for the National Books Critics Circle Award, will visit on February 2nd and 3rd, 2017. Bernadette Mayer is an American poet, writer, and visual artist associated with both the Language poets and the New York School. Mayer&amp;rsquo;s record-keeping and use of stream-of-consciousness narrative are two trademarks of her writing, though she is also known for her work with form and mythology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will Alexander, Tisa Bryant, Robin Coste Lewis and Donal Fox in a Planned Parenthood benefit at Blum &amp; Poe, LA</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/will-alexander-tisa-bryant-robin-coste-lewis-and-donal-fox-in-a-planned-parenthood-benefit-at-blum-poe-la/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 06:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/will-alexander-tisa-bryant-robin-coste-lewis-and-donal-fox-in-a-planned-parenthood-benefit-at-blum-poe-la/</guid>
      <description>An evening of Poetry &amp;amp; Music at Blum &amp;amp; Poe, Los Angeles in conjunction with Sam Durant’s exhibition Build Therefore Your Own World
Featuring:
A reading of new work by poets Will Alexander, Tisa Bryant, and Robin Coste Lewis
A solo performance by Donal Fox featuring single piano works such as Star Spangled Banner Fractured, Peace Out, My Brother.
Doors open at 7 pm
Event begins at 7:30 pm
$10 suggested donation All proceeds will go to Planned Parenthood</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jimmy Santiago Baca at the University of New Mexico</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/jimmy-santiago-baca-at-the-university-of-new-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 06:22:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/jimmy-santiago-baca-at-the-university-of-new-mexico/</guid>
      <description>Critically acclaimed Mexican American poet, writer, and activist, Jimmy Santiago Baca will be coming to the University of New Mexico campus on Tuesday, January 31st. Mr. Baca will be hosting a writing workshop at 3:00 p.m. in Room 104 of the Education Building. Later in the evening, at 7:00 p.m. in SUB Ballroom B, Mr. Baca will be speaking and doing a book signing. Don&amp;rsquo;t miss the chance to learn from this inspirational artist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thalia Field, Jim Shepard, Karen Joy Fowler, Julie Carr, Miranda Mellis and Laura Mullen reading with Solid Objects at The Kitchen</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/thalia-field-jim-shepard-karen-joy-fowler-julie-carr-miranda-mellis-and-laura-mullen-reading-with-solid-objects-at-the-kitchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 19:37:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/thalia-field-jim-shepard-karen-joy-fowler-julie-carr-miranda-mellis-and-laura-mullen-reading-with-solid-objects-at-the-kitchen/</guid>
      <description>A benefit for the NONHUMAN RIGHTS PROJECT and the NATURAL RESOURCES DEFENSE COUNCIL with a screening of an excerpt from UNLOCKING THE CAGE, Chris Hegedus and D.A. Pennebaker&amp;rsquo;s groundbreaking film about animal rights and the legal system.
All proceeds from book sales and admissions (pay what you wish at the door) will go to the Nonhuman Rights Project and the Natural Resources Defense Council.
Refreshments will be served.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Glass Menagerie on Broadway</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/the-glass-menagerie-on-broadway/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 18:03:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/the-glass-menagerie-on-broadway/</guid>
      <description>Sally Field &amp;amp; Joe Mantello star in The Glass Menagerie on Broadway. Two-time Academy Award® winner Sally Field and two-time Tony Award® winner Joe Mantello star in Tennessee Williams’ The Glass Menagerie on Broadway. Also starring Finn Wittrock and Madison Ferris. Tony winner Sam Gold directs.
The Glass Menagerie is the play that brought a brilliant young writer named Tennessee Williams to national attention when it premiered on Broadway in 1945.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Osama Alomar at Evanston Writers Resist in Illinois</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/osama-alomar-at-evanston-writers-resist-in-illinois/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 02:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/osama-alomar-at-evanston-writers-resist-in-illinois/</guid>
      <description>On 1/15/17, over 75 Chicago writers, in seven events around the city, will join writers worldwide for #writersresist, a “re-inauguration” of compassion, equality, free speech, and the fundamental ideals of democracy. Chicago Book Expo and Rhino Poetry are proud to present the Evanston edition of this event, including featured readers Osama Alomar, Veronica Arreola, Virginia Bell, Dina Elenbogen, Pamela Ferdinand, Aricka Foreman, Ralph Hamilton, Maudlyne Ihejirika, Parneshia Jones, Bennett Johnson, C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Keene, Ann Lauterbach, Michael Silverblatt, and Anne Waldman reading from Kenward Elmslie’s The Orchid Stories at the Poetry Project</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/john-keene-ann-lauterbach-michael-silverblatt-and-anne-waldman-reading-from-kenward-elmslies-the-orchid-stories-at-the-poetry-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 01:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/john-keene-ann-lauterbach-michael-silverblatt-and-anne-waldman-reading-from-kenward-elmslies-the-orchid-stories-at-the-poetry-project/</guid>
      <description>The Song Cave presents a new edition of Kenward Elmslie’s out-of-print masterpiece, The Orchid Stories, with a night of readings from the book, featuring John Keene, Ann Lauterbach, Michael Silverblatt, and Anne Waldman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mei-mei Berssenbrugge, Souvankham Thammavongsa and Ari Banias at Quiet: A Poetry Reading for Agnes Martin</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/mei-mei-berssenbrugge-souvankham-thammavongsa-and-ari-banias-at-quiet-a-poetry-reading-for-agnes-martin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 17:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/mei-mei-berssenbrugge-souvankham-thammavongsa-and-ari-banias-at-quiet-a-poetry-reading-for-agnes-martin/</guid>
      <description>Poets Ari Banias, Mei-mei Berssenbrugge, and Souvankham Thammavongsa read selections of their work in honor of Agnes Martin in an evening curated by artist Jen Bervin. The program concludes with a reception, including a book signing with the three poets, and an exhibition viewing of Agnes Martin.
In-kind support for this program is provided by the Academy of American Poets.
$15, $10 members, $5 students via button below. Free student tickets are no longer available for this event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anne Carson poetry reading at NYU</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/anne-carson-poetry-reading-at-nyu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 17:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/anne-carson-poetry-reading-at-nyu/</guid>
      <description>The New York University Creative Writing Program’s Spring 2017 Reading Series begins with a reading from its faculty members, among which is Anne Carson, Distinguished Poet-in-Residence. Anne Carson is also a MacArthur Fellow, the winner of the T.S. Eliot Prize for Poetry and her books have been shortlisted for the National Book Critics Circle Award and the T.S. Eliot Prize, as well as the Forward Prize.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gary Snyder &amp; Tom Killion at Wild &amp; Scenic Film Festival, Nevada County, California</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/gary-snyder-tom-killion-at-wild-scenic-film-festival-nevada-county-california/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 05:16:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/gary-snyder-tom-killion-at-wild-scenic-film-festival-nevada-county-california/</guid>
      <description>Gary Snyder &amp;amp; Tom Killion present an evening of film, conversation, and poetry focused on the role arts play in the environmental movement.
As a festival by activists and for activists, Wild &amp;amp; Scenic is organized and produced by SYRCL (the South Yuba River Citizens League). Since 1983, they’ve been building a community to protect and restore the rivers of their home watershed, from source to sea. The Wild &amp;amp; Scenic Film Festival puts local and global work into the broader environmental and social context, and serves to remind the audience that everyone is a participant in the global movement for a more wild and scenic world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoko Tawada at Nuyorican Poets Cafe</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/yoko-tawada-at-nuyorican-poets-cafe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/yoko-tawada-at-nuyorican-poets-cafe/</guid>
      <description>Yoko Tawada will be speaking at the upcoming translation panel, New Literature from Europe Presents: From One Language to Another, at the Nuyorican Poets Cafe.
The event is hosted in coordination with ALTA and the Nuyorican. Tickets are $8 in advance on their website and $12 at the door.
Yoko Tawada was born in Tokyo in 1960, moved to Hamburg when she was twenty-two, and then to Berlin in 2006. She writes in both Japanese and German, and has published several books—stories, novels, poems, plays, essays—in both languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Hora de Clarice: Clarice Lispector&#39;s Birthday at Instituto Moreira Sallas </title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/a-hora-de-clarice-clarice-lispectors-birthday-at-instituto-moreira-sallas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/a-hora-de-clarice-clarice-lispectors-birthday-at-instituto-moreira-sallas/</guid>
      <description>A Hora de Clarice, an annual celebration in honor of the Brazilian writer Clarice Lispector&amp;rsquo;s birthday, has been running in Brazil for the last five years with simultaneous celebrations in Paris, Madrid, Lisbon, Frankfurt, Buenos Aires, and Mexico City. Please toast to Clarice with fellow readers and lovers of the great woman and her work on December 10, 2016, at the Instituto Moreira Sallas.
At 4:30 PM, please come and listen to Lispector translators Katrina Dodson and Paloma Vidal in conversation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scarred Hearts Screening</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/scarred-hearts-screening/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 17:31:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/scarred-hearts-screening/</guid>
      <description>Scarred Hearts: New York Premiere
 141 m. Radu Jude.Romania/Germany. Romanian with subtitles. NR.  Romania, 1937. A young man spends his days at a sanatorium on the Black Sea coast, suffering from bone tuberculosis. Falling in love with another patient, he narrates their attempts to live life to the fullest as their bodies slowly fade away but their minds refuse to give up. This refreshingly unconventional drama is loosely based on Jewish Romanian author Max Blecher’s autobiographical novel Scarred Hearts, written before he died at age 29, after ten years of suffering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Hora de Clarice: Clarice Lispector&#39;s Birthday at Picture Room</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/a-hora-de-clarice-clarice-lispectors-birthday-at-picture-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 15:26:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/a-hora-de-clarice-clarice-lispectors-birthday-at-picture-room/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re throwing a birthday party for Clarice Lispector! Join us on Saturday, December 10th at 6pm at Picture Room.
A Hora de Clarice, an annual celebration in honor of the Brazilian writer Clarice Lispector&amp;rsquo;s birthday, has been running in Brazil for the last five years with simultaneous celebrations in Paris, Madrid, Lisbon, Frankfurt, Buenos Aires, and Mexico City. Please join us on December 10th, 2016, as we toast the great Clarice and celebrate the recent translations of her work published by New Directions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eliot Weinberger at the Nuyorican Poets Cafe</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/eliot-weinberger-at-the-nuyorican-poets-cafe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 16:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/eliot-weinberger-at-the-nuyorican-poets-cafe/</guid>
      <description>Eliot Weinberger will be joined by acclaimed European and American poets in this Evening of Poetry and Prose at the Nuyorican Poets Cafe.
Tickets are $8 - $12.
Eliot Weinberger is an essayist, political commentator, translator, and editor. His books of avant-gardist literary essays include Karmic Traces, An Elemental Thing (named by the Village Voice as one of the &amp;ldquo;20 Best Books of the Year&amp;rdquo;) and, most recently, Oranges &amp;amp; Peanuts for Sale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rediscovering Roger Lewinter: Lydia Davis, Rachel Careau and Saul Anton at Albertine</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/rediscovering-roger-lewinter-lydia-davis-rachel-careau-and-saul-anton-at-albertine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 15:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/rediscovering-roger-lewinter-lydia-davis-rachel-careau-and-saul-anton-at-albertine/</guid>
      <description>Join Lydia Davis and Rachel Careau as they discuss the life and work of author Roger Lewinter.
This event is in English, free and open to the public, with no RSVP necessary.
Roger Lewinter was born in Montauban, France, in 1941, to Austrian Jewish parents. The family moved to Switzerland during the war, and he has lived much of his life in Geneva. For more than forty years he has worked as a writer (of both literary and scholarly works), an editor, and a translator (of Georg Groddeck, Karl Kraus, Elias Canetti, Robert Walser, and Rilke, among others).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jen Bervin at Illinois State University Galleries</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/jen-bervin-at-illinois-state-university-galleries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 18:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/jen-bervin-at-illinois-state-university-galleries/</guid>
      <description>Jen Bervin will be giving a lecture free and open to the public at the University Galleries affiliated with Illinois State University. It is part of their symposium “Oscillations of Gender and Genre&amp;rdquo;.
Registration is not required. For more information or to arrange special accommodations, please call the University Galleries at (309) 438-5487 or email them at gallery@ilstu.edu .
Jen Bervin is a Brooklyn-based visual artist and writer whose works often combine strong conceptual elements and a minimalist’s eye for the poetic and essential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peter Cole Reads with Ange Mlinko, in Celebration of Joel Shapiro Exhibition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/peter-cole-reads-with-ange-mlinko-in-celebration-of-joel-shapiro-exhibition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 15:03:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/peter-cole-reads-with-ange-mlinko-in-celebration-of-joel-shapiro-exhibition/</guid>
      <description>Along with his other recent work, Peter Cole will read original poems written in celebration of sculptor Joel Shapiro&amp;rsquo;s new exhibition at the Dominique Lévy Gallery. His work and that of other featured artists, including poet Ange Mlinko, will then be published in a monograph in conjunction with the exhibition.
RSVP REQUIRED: Please email sylvia@dominique-levy.com or call +1 212 772 2004.
Contemporary American poet and noted translator of Hebrew, Peter Cole’s most recent book of poems is The Invention of Influence, which follows his remarkable collection Things on Which I’ve Stumbled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forrest Gander on translating Pablo Neruda at Harvard</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/forrest-gander-on-translating-pablo-neruda-at-harvard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 15:12:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/forrest-gander-on-translating-pablo-neruda-at-harvard/</guid>
      <description>Poet and translator Forrest Gander will be discussing his experiences translating his latest project, Then Come Back: The Lost Neruda, an anthology of poet Pablo Neruda&amp;rsquo;s work.
This event is free and open to the public.
Forrest Gander (1956– ) was born in the Mojave Desert and grew up, for the most part, in Virginia. Trenchant periods of his life were spent in San Francisco, Dolores Hidalgo (Mexico), and Eureka Springs, Arkansas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thomas Merton is focus of lecture series at St. Mary’s Episcopal Church</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/thomas-merton-is-focus-of-lecture-series-at-st-marys-episcopal-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 16:01:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/thomas-merton-is-focus-of-lecture-series-at-st-marys-episcopal-church/</guid>
      <description>Thomas Merton is the focus of an upcoming lecture series at St. Mary&amp;rsquo;s Episcopal Church in Anchorage, Alaska. Merton spent much time traveling in Alaska prior to his death in 1968.
Reverend Grant&amp;rsquo;s lecture schedule is as follows:
November 4, 7:00pm : &amp;ldquo;The Spiritual Path of Contemplation and Action: Insights from the life of Thomas Merton&amp;rdquo;
November 5, 10:00am : &amp;ldquo;Practicing Contemplation and Action: A Quiet Day for Self-Inquiry and Devotion&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoko Tawada at the New Literature from Europe Festival</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/yoko-tawada-at-the-new-literature-from-europe-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 15:44:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/yoko-tawada-at-the-new-literature-from-europe-festival/</guid>
      <description>Yoko Tawada will be performing at The New Literature from Europe Festival. This annual festival features readings and discussions between leading and emerging literary voices from Europe, and some of America’s foremost writers and critics. NLE celebrates important new European literature in translation such as Tawada&amp;rsquo;s forthcoming novel, Memoirs of a Polar Bear, which will be available in November.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/R_55U0MVNXNsHFWop0I8qK0OhYlG3l_EPWPTax0VEALEAKdY8mxZ_U2tLi5rZcRGudENhc8_voX9JowmZ2xM7RnsPEpW=s600)](/webhook-uploads/1468598296440/Tawada.jpg) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoko Tawada and Susan Bernofsky at New Literature from Europe Festival</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/yoko-tawada-and-susan-bernofsky-at-new-literature-from-europe-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 14:28:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/yoko-tawada-and-susan-bernofsky-at-new-literature-from-europe-festival/</guid>
      <description>Yoko Tawada moved to Hamburg when she was twenty-two from her native Japan. In 2006, she moved to Berlin where she now lives. She writes in both Japanese and German, and has published several books—stories, novels, poems, plays, essays—in both languages.
The New Yorker said Tawada’s work compares to Bruno Schulz, Silvina Ocampo or Franz Kafka and, “is characterized by concordances one doesn’t know what to make of and perceptions that may or may not need to be discounted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simon Starling: At Twilight, Japan Society NYC</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/simon-starling-at-twilight-japan-society-nyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 15:36:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/simon-starling-at-twilight-japan-society-nyc/</guid>
      <description>At the height of WWI, poet W. B . Yeats collaborated with members of the avant garde to stage his Japanese noh inspired dance play At the Hawk&amp;rsquo;s Well (1916). To mark its centennial, Turner Prize winner Simon Starling reinterprets this production in an exhibition that illustrates the impact of noh on Western Modernism. Newly created masks, costumes, and a dance on video are paired with works by the 20th-century masters connected to Yeats&amp;rsquo; play, bringing to life Starling&amp;rsquo;s irrepressible inventiveness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michael McClure at Diesel Books</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/michael-mcclure-at-diesel-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 14:46:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/michael-mcclure-at-diesel-books/</guid>
      <description>Michael McClure will be reading from his upcoming book of poetry, Mephistos and Other Poems, at Diesel Books in Oakland, CA.
This is a free event. For more information, call (510) 653-9965 or email events@dieselbookstore.com .
Michael McClure is one of the major figures of the Beat Generation. Besides reading at the famous San Francisco Six Gallery Reading where Ginsberg first read &amp;ldquo;Howl,&amp;rdquo; he was fictionalized in Jack Kerouac’s novel Big Sur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michael McClure at Moe&#39;s Books</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/michael-mcclure-at-moes-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 14:41:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/michael-mcclure-at-moes-books/</guid>
      <description>Michael McClure will be reading from his upcoming book of poetry, Mephistos and Other Poems, at Moe&amp;rsquo;s Books in Berkeley, CA.
This is a free event. For more information, call (510) 849-2087 .
Michael McClure is one of the major figures of the Beat Generation. Besides reading at the famous San Francisco Six Gallery Reading where Ginsberg first read &amp;ldquo;Howl,&amp;rdquo; he was fictionalized in Jack Kerouac’s novel Big Sur. McClure is a captivating reader and performer (he recited from The Canterbury Tales in Martin Scorcese’s The Last Waltz) and his collaboration with The Doors’ keyboardist Ray Manzarek and contemporary composer Terry Riley are now legendary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michael McClure at City Lights Books</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/michael-mcclure-at-city-lights-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 14:35:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/michael-mcclure-at-city-lights-books/</guid>
      <description>Michael McClure will be reading from his upcoming book of poetry, Mephistos and Other Poems, at City Lights Books in San Francisco.
This is a free event.
Michael McClure is one of the major figures of the Beat Generation. Besides reading at the famous San Francisco Six Gallery Reading where Ginsberg first read &amp;ldquo;Howl,&amp;rdquo; he was fictionalized in Jack Kerouac’s novel Big Sur. McClure is a captivating reader and performer (he recited from The Canterbury Tales in Martin Scorcese’s The Last Waltz) and his collaboration with The Doors’ keyboardist Ray Manzarek and contemporary composer Terry Riley are now legendary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Group Spirit with Toni Basil and Michael McClure</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/group-spirit-with-toni-basil-and-michael-mcclure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 14:26:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/group-spirit-with-toni-basil-and-michael-mcclure/</guid>
      <description>Michael McClure joins Toni Basil as part of the Bruce Conner: I AM/I AM NOT exhibition at SFMOMA. He will be reading excerpts from The Mandala Book, his collaboration with Conner.
Tickets are $15 general; $12 members.
Michael McClure is one of the major figures of the Beat Generation. Besides reading at the famous San Francisco Six Gallery Reading where Ginsberg first read &amp;ldquo;Howl,&amp;rdquo; he was fictionalized in Jack Kerouac’s novel Big Sur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anne Carson with Michael Silverblatt at Readings and Conversations</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/anne-carson-with-michael-silverblatt-at-readings-and-conversations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 20:47:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/anne-carson-with-michael-silverblatt-at-readings-and-conversations/</guid>
      <description>The Lannan Foundation&amp;rsquo;s Readings and Conversations will be hosting Anne Carson alongside Michael Silverblatt at the Lensic Performing Arts Center in Santa Fe.
Tickets are $6 to the general public and $3 with student ID. They can be purchased over the phone at (505) 988-1234, or in person at the box office, from 10:00 - 4:00 Monday through Friday, or from noon - showtime on weekends. Alternatively, tickets can be purchased online at http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Susan Howe in the Schlesinger Visiting Writer Series at Yale</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/susan-howe-in-the-schlesinger-visiting-writer-series-at-yale/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 20:12:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/susan-howe-in-the-schlesinger-visiting-writer-series-at-yale/</guid>
      <description>Susan Howe will be speaking at the Schlesinger Visiting Writer Series hosted by Yale University this November. This event is open to the general public. For more information, contact the Department of English at (203) 432-2233.
About Susan Howe:
Author of more than a dozen books of poetry and two of literary criticism, Susan Howe&amp;rsquo;s recent collection of poems That This, published by New Directions won the Bollingen Prize in 2011.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Evening with Reiner Stach and Kurt Beals at Deutsches Haus</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/an-evening-with-reiner-stach-and-kurt-beals-at-deutsches-haus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 19:19:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/an-evening-with-reiner-stach-and-kurt-beals-at-deutsches-haus/</guid>
      <description>Deutsches Haus at NYU presents a reading by Reiner Stach from his recent nonfiction book Is that Kafka? 99 Finds, followed by a conversation between the author and the acclaimed translator of the book, Kurt Beals.
In the course of compiling his highly acclaimed three-volume biography of Kafka, while foraying to libraries and archives from Prague to Israel, Reiner Stach made one astounding discovery after another: unexpected photographs, inconsistencies in handwritten texts, excerpts from letters, and testimonies from Kafka&amp;rsquo;s contemporaries that shed surprising light on his personality and his writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarice Lispector Translated: Katrina Dodson at Vanderbilt University</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/clarice-lispector-translated-katrina-dodson-at-vanderbilt-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 19:14:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/clarice-lispector-translated-katrina-dodson-at-vanderbilt-university/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/_eEMOnCs1c_6484ZtfzN1cs9lFVj5pQCrWjDDr4Br1nXDSQUJCpXFrnyhc8nGa7Re3_XkLhPX8eyMyGQ0tB3M6NsG5Ih=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1476213197806/Dodson-3-662x1024.jpg) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LispectorFest at the University of Tennessee, Knoxville</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/lispectorfest-at-the-university-of-tennessee-knoxville/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 19:06:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/lispectorfest-at-the-university-of-tennessee-knoxville/</guid>
      <description>Join Katrina Dodson, recepient of the 2016 PEN Translation Prize for The Complete Stories, for a celebration of Clarice Lispector&amp;rsquo;s work in Tennessee.
EVENTS:
Tuesday, October 18 6:00 PM Film Screening: The Hour of the Star Directed by Suzana Amaral Discussion to follow led by Eurídice Silva-Filho, associate professor, Department of Modern Foreign Languages and Literatures Hodges Library, Auditorium
**Wednesday, October 19 **Keynote Lecture 4:00 PM - 5:30 PM Rediscovering Clarice Katrina Dodson, PhD, Translator of The Complete Stories by Clarice Lispector and winner of the 2016 PEN Translation prize Hodges Library, Auditorium</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bernadette Mayer, Philip Good and William Lessard at Berl&#39;s Brooklyn Poetry Shop</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/bernadette-mayer-philip-good-and-william-lessard-at-berls-brooklyn-poetry-shop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 14:36:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/bernadette-mayer-philip-good-and-william-lessard-at-berls-brooklyn-poetry-shop/</guid>
      <description>Hear Bernadette Mayer read from her most recent collection Works and Days. Also reading: Philip Good and William Lessard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alexander Kluge &amp; Ben Lerner at Goethe-Institut</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/alexander-kluge-ben-lerner-at-goethe-institut/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 23:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/alexander-kluge-ben-lerner-at-goethe-institut/</guid>
      <description>One of the undisputed intellectual giants of postwar Germany, Alexander Kluge is a writer, theorist, filmmaker, and television pioneer with a prolific career spanning almost six decades. His reputation in the US, however, is still narrowly associated with the 1962 Oberhausen Manifesto calling for a “new German film,” as well as with his acclaimed films of the 1970s. This fall, the Goethe-Institut, Anthology Film Archives, and the Museum of Modern Art honor Kluge’s interdisciplinary oeuvre in its varied expressions, introducing selected works for the first time to local audiences as well as revisiting with him some of the beloved older ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alexander Kluge at Anthology Film Archives</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/alexander-kluge-at-anthology-film-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 23:04:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/alexander-kluge-at-anthology-film-archives/</guid>
      <description>When Anthology Film Archives opened its doors at 32 Second Avenue in 1988, the first series they presented was an Alexander Kluge retrospective. A central figure in the formation of the New German Cinema, a student of Theodor Adorno, and author across several media, Kluge is one of the most vital postwar European artists. He also remains one of the most active, even if his latter-day work is largely unknown on this side of the Atlantic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three short films and an evening with Alexander Kluge</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/three-short-films-and-an-evening-with-alexander-kluge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 14:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/three-short-films-and-an-evening-with-alexander-kluge/</guid>
      <description>Fifty years on, Alexander Kluge is best known as a leading figure of the New German Cinema, born of the 1962 Oberhausen Manifesto. Yet his seminal filmmaking of the 1960s and 1970s is paralleled by his subsequent work as a writer, theorist, and film and television director. Publications pairing Kluge’s writing with the photography of Gerhard Richter, a collaboration with artist duo DAS INSTITUT (Kerstin Brätsch and Adele Röder), and boundary-pushing television productions all testify to the genre-defying vision of a true pioneer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tribute to Enrique Vila-Matas at McNally Jackson </title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/tribute-to-enrique-vila-matas-at-mcnally-jackson/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 16:03:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/tribute-to-enrique-vila-matas-at-mcnally-jackson/</guid>
      <description>On the occasion of the publication of Vampire in Love, McNally Jackson is hosting a tribute event to Enrique Vila-Matas.
The event will bring together Enrique Vila-Matas, Eduardo Lago, Valeria Luiselli, Alvaro Enrigue, Sergio Chejfec, Graciela Montaldo and Julio Villanueva Chang.
The event will take place in Spanish, followed by a bilingual Q&amp;amp;A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Katrina Dodson at Us&amp;Them Reading Series at ALTA39</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/katrina-dodson-at-usthem-reading-series-at-alta39/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 19:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/katrina-dodson-at-usthem-reading-series-at-alta39/</guid>
      <description>Translator Katrina Dodson will be reading selections from The Complete Stories by Clarice Lispector as part of Us&amp;amp;Them: A Writer/Translator reading series at the 39th annual ALTA Conference on Saturday, October 8th, 2016. She will also be reading an essay written for the Believer based on the journal chronicling her experiences while translating Lispector&amp;rsquo;s work.
Katrina Dodson&amp;rsquo;s work has appeared in Granta, McSweeney&amp;rsquo;s, and Two Lines. She holds a PhD in comparative literature at the University of California, Berkeley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Literary Death Match</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/literary-death-match/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 20:18:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/literary-death-match/</guid>
      <description>Literary Death Match is teaming with the masterminds at ALTA for an all-out night of brilliant lit that will pit translators versus the translated, plus comedic styling and enough tomfoolery to bring you to your feet.
Literary Death Match features four writers who read their own work for seven minutes or less, who are then judged by three all-star judges. They select two finalists to compete in the Literary Death Match finale, a vaguely literary game to decide the ultimate winner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pen Translation Committee Reads at KGB Bar</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/pen-translation-committee-reads-at-kgb-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 20:02:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/pen-translation-committee-reads-at-kgb-bar/</guid>
      <description>The KGB Bar Sunday Night fiction showcases the finest in contemporary fiction from new and emerging writers.
Robert Bononno will read from A Roll of the Dice by Stéphane Mallarmé.
Heather Cleary will read from No-Tell Motel by Florencia Werchowsky.
Jonathan Cohen will read from Hurricane Neruda by Pedro Mir.
Lyn Miller-Lachmann will read from The World in a Second by Isabel Minhós Martins and Bernardo Carvalho.
Kyoo Lee will read from works by Hyesoon Kim and Olsoo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eka Kurniawan in DC </title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/eka-kurniawan-in-dc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 19:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/eka-kurniawan-in-dc/</guid>
      <description>Eka Kurniawan will be in DC for two public events on September 28th.
12:00-01:30 PM — East-West Center
Reading in cooperation with American University’s ASEAN Studies Initiative, at 1819 L St NW #600, Washington, DC 20036
6:30PM — Kramerbooks &amp;amp; Afterwords Cafe
Books signing and evening discussion at 1517 Connecticut Ave NW, Washington, DC 20036
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/T6YgfCviV7H67mPXE9-SjOBBJev8u4Qs-zfFPJqIVeBk-okb5FqyzHP-REsBhVLu_N8td7f2UPLHkOpi3Gz5OYKPwkba=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1474319749072/Eka%20Kurniawan_ND.sm.6579.jpg) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mei-Mei Berssenbrugge and Richard Tuttle</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/mei-mei-berssenbrugge-and-richard-tuttle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 20:58:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/mei-mei-berssenbrugge-and-richard-tuttle/</guid>
      <description>$10 general admission; $6 admission for students and seniors; Advance ticket purchases are recommended; visit www.diaart.org/poetry. Tickets are also available for purchase at the door, subject to availability
Mei-Mei Berssenbrugge is a poet and editor who lives and works in New Mexico and New York. She received an MFA from Columbia University, New York. Berssenbrugge is the author of twelve books of poetry, including Hello, The Roses (New Directions, 2013). She has been a contributing editor at Conjunctions Magazine since 1978.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sylvia Legris at the International Festival of Authors in Toronto</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/sylvia-legris-at-the-international-festival-of-authors-in-toronto/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 15:57:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/sylvia-legris-at-the-international-festival-of-authors-in-toronto/</guid>
      <description>Sylvia Legris and Takashi Hiraide will both be reading at the 37th annual International Festival of Authors in Toronto. Since 1974, the festival has welcomed more than 9,000 authors from over 100 countries, including 22 Nobel Laureates and countless other award winners.
Sunday, October 23rd at 5pm: &amp;ldquo;Interrupting Familiar Spaces&amp;rdquo;
Reading and conversation between Takashi Hiraide, Sylvia Legris, Donna Morrissey, Sarah Pinder
Wednesday, October 26th at 8pm: &amp;ldquo;Sound &amp;amp; Voice&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rivka Galchen: BBF Bookend Event </title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/rivka-galchen-bbf-bookend-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 19:36:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/rivka-galchen-bbf-bookend-event/</guid>
      <description>The Brooklyn Book Festival and Harper&amp;rsquo;s Magazine present &amp;ldquo;Writing and Motherhood/Writing on Motherhood&amp;rdquo; at Book Culture on Columbus.
Authors Rivka Galchen (Little Labors) and Heidi Julavits (The Folded Clock) will discuss writing about motherhood and writing while mothering. There&amp;rsquo;s an art to both, and a process, in addition to a lot of hard work and love. Moderated by Giulia Melucci (Harper&amp;rsquo;s Magazine/I Loved, I Lost, I Made Spaghetti)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rosmarie Waldrop reading with Lynn Xu at the jubilat/Jones Reading Series</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/rosmarie-waldrop-reading-with-lynn-xu-at-the-jubilatjones-reading-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 14:23:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/rosmarie-waldrop-reading-with-lynn-xu-at-the-jubilatjones-reading-series/</guid>
      <description>Rosmarie Waldrop and Lynn Xu, will be reading in the Goodwin Room at the Jones Library in Amherst, Massachusetts, on September 18th at 3pm.
Born in Germany, Rosmarie Waldrop immigrated to the US in 1958. She has a Ph.D. in Comparative Literature from the University of Michigan and has taught at Wesleyan, Tufts, and Brown Universities. She lives in Providence, Rhode Island, with Keith Waldrop (with whom she also co-edits Burning Deck Press).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enrique Vila-Matas with Paul Auster and Valeria Luiselli at the Instituto Cervantes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/enrique-vila-matas-with-paul-auster-and-valeria-luiselli-at-the-instituto-cervantes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 20:38:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/enrique-vila-matas-with-paul-auster-and-valeria-luiselli-at-the-instituto-cervantes/</guid>
      <description>Please join us at the Instituto Cervantes for a celebration of Vampire in Love by Enrique Vila-Matas.
On Wednesday, October 5th, Valeria Luiselli will moderate a conversation between Paul Auster and Enrique Vila-Matas. The event will take place in Spanish, with simultaneous translation.
Vampire in Love is a selection of the Spanish master&amp;rsquo;s finest short stories. An effeminate, hunchbacked barber on the verge of death falls in love with a choirboy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sylvia Legris, Will Alexander, Carlos Lara &amp; Marcella Durand at Berl&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/sylvia-legris-will-alexander-carlos-lara-marcella-durand-at-berls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 14:36:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/sylvia-legris-will-alexander-carlos-lara-marcella-durand-at-berls/</guid>
      <description>Join Sylvia Legris, Will Alexander, Carlos Lara and Marcella Durand for an evening of reading at Berl&amp;rsquo;s Brooklyn Poetry Shop (the only all poetry bookstore in NYC). The event is free and open to the public.
Sylvia Legris’ latest poetry collection is The Hideous Hidden (Forthcoming from New Directions). Her collection Nerve Squall won both the 2006 Griffin Poetry Prize and the 2006 Pat Lowther Award. Her poems have appeared in many publications, including The New Yorker, Granta, Poetry, and Conjunctions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judgement at Nuremberg by Abby Mann, Touring 2016-17</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/judgement-at-nuremberg-by-abby-mann-touring-2016-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 20:43:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/judgement-at-nuremberg-by-abby-mann-touring-2016-17/</guid>
      <description>As the world commemorates the 75th anniversary of World War II, and as politics continues to infiltrate human rights and social justice issues worldwide, L.A. Theatre Works tours one of the great courtroom dramas of the last century: Judgment at Nuremberg.
Ostensibly, the American-led tribunals were formed to prosecute those accused of war crimes committed during WWII against Jews, Gypsies, homosexuals, people who were mentally and physically handicapped, and those considered inferior to the Aryan Race.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Horacio Castellanos Moya: Reading and Q&amp;A</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/horacio-castellanos-moya-reading-and-qa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 19:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/horacio-castellanos-moya-reading-and-qa/</guid>
      <description>Come join Horacio Castellanos Moya for a reading and Q&amp;amp;A at the Heyman Center for the Humanities at Columbia University.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/IkhWejoVM-8QH6jxIyp9ZZL2QrMX23MOytR2HvjyWj4Lt5aU7d_1Jxf3imqpkgGv-JlCzruIhFsVR_PQc9KVUAGduKfb=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1471891306640/Castellanos%20Moya%204.tif) Horacio Castellanos Moya is a writer and a journalist from El Salvador. For two decades he worked as the editor of news agencies, magazines and newspapers in Mexico, Guatemala and his own country. He has published eleven novels, five short story collections and two essay collections. His novels have been translated into eleven languages; six of them ( Revulsion: Thomas Bernhard in El Salvador, The Dream of My Return, Senselessness, The She-Devil in the Mirror, Dance with Snakes, and Tyrant Memory) are available in English.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoshimasu Gozo &amp; Forrest Gander at the Center for the Art of Translation, San Francisco</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/yoshimasu-gozo-forrest-gander-at-the-center-for-the-art-of-translation-san-francisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 18:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/yoshimasu-gozo-forrest-gander-at-the-center-for-the-art-of-translation-san-francisco/</guid>
      <description>“Gozo Yoshimasu is, simply put, one of a handful of the most important and influential living poets whose work has taken poetry into the beyond.” -Forrest Gander
The Center for the Art of Translation welcomes Japanese poet and performance artist Yoshimasu Gozo and poet Forrest Gander to San Francisco for a performance and discussion of Gozo’s work, including upcoming poetry collection Alice Iris Red Horse. Edited by Gander, Alice Iris Red Horse gathers translations of Gozo’s major works that span his entire career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eliot Weinberger at Seminary Co-op</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/eliot-weinberger-at-seminary-co-op/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 16:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/eliot-weinberger-at-seminary-co-op/</guid>
      <description>Eliot Weinberger will appear at Seminary Co-Op Bookstore to discuss his two recent projects, The Ghosts of Birds and _Nineteen Ways of Looking at Wang Wei. _
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/cN9_-YiPgks53U6bUaur3i5KfV9a8fg4NZZZPQROE47BW0n7iZy6qWphz3GafeC024JnRJPPnska3T3X4B6zoxR5rCI=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1476716468164/Eliot%20Weinberger_select_6656.ND.jpg) The Ghosts of Birds offers thirty-five essays by Eliot Weinberger: the first section of the book continues his linked serial-essay, An Elemental Thing, which pulls the reader into “a vortex for the entire universe” (Boston Review). Here, Weinberger chronicles a nineteenth-century journey down the Colorado River, records the dreams of people named Chang, and shares other factually verifiable discoveries that seem too fabulous to possibly be true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eliot Weinberger and Katie Raissian at McNally Jackson</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/eliot-weinberger-and-katie-raissian-at-mcnally-jackson/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 16:22:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/eliot-weinberger-and-katie-raissian-at-mcnally-jackson/</guid>
      <description>Please join us for the New York launch of Eliot Weinberger&amp;rsquo;s new essay collection, The Ghosts of Birds, at McNally Jackson. Reading to be followed by a conversation between Eliot Weinberger and Katie Raissian, Editor-in-Chief of Stonecutter Journal.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/tO9K81pdwO3EIqxUqAnIraFNN6scXeGdBvsH0mQMI7zpUVZRbT2JSqoylqnErBvLqiaiMFaQSnVpAn5BC91JNEwsx90=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1476716566608/Eliot%20Weinberger_select_6656.ND.jpg) ELIOT WEINBERGER is an essayist, political commentator, translator, and editor. His books of avant-gardist literary essays include Karmic Traces, An Elemental Thing (named by the Village Voice as one of the &amp;ldquo;20 Best Books of the Year&amp;rdquo;) and, Oranges &amp;amp; Peanuts for Sale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gozo Yoshimasu: marteau</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/gozo-yoshimasu-marteau/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 20:54:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/gozo-yoshimasu-marteau/</guid>
      <description>Blank Forms presents Yoshimasu Gozo at Off Vendome
Tickets 12 dollars advance/15 day of, 8 dollars members
In performance, Gozo Yoshimasu’s language is incantatory and strange. He breaks down Japanese into phonemes, counterpointed sonic progressions, and rhymes. Often, he’ll include fragments of English, French, Chinese, Okinawan or Korean and, on paper, he uses multiple scripts—romanji, Korean hungul, and invented man’yo-gana and pictographs as well as normal Japanese kanji, hiragana, and katakana.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Directions/Christine Burgin at The NY Art Book Fair</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/new-directionschristine-burgin-at-the-ny-art-book-fair/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 16:41:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/new-directionschristine-burgin-at-the-ny-art-book-fair/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/PCTB84lo8_DGP2aX3HM1t7PMVsxwBKA-WtuODDqg5z8fM_R9xsMzhzq6kO673iEkR_rgei77Ypl2JBUwXihUnHZfTfo=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1472502766100/new2016nyabf.jpeg) Free and open to the public, the NY Art Book Fair is the world’s premier event for artists’ books, catalogs, monographs, periodicals, and zines.
Last year, the fair featured over 370 booksellers, antiquarians, artists, institutions and independent publishers from twenty-eight countries. The 2015 NY Art Book Fair was attended by more than 35,000 people.
Come say hello to Christine Burgin and Mieke Chew at the New Directions &amp;amp; Christine Burgin Gallery table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoshimasu Gozo and Forrest Gander at The Poetry Project</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/yoshimasu-gozo-and-forrest-gander-at-the-poetry-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 14:17:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/yoshimasu-gozo-and-forrest-gander-at-the-poetry-project/</guid>
      <description>Come see Yoshimasu Gozo and Forrest Gander perform at The Poetry Project.
Forrest Gander is the author of numerous books of poetry, fiction, translation, and essays (his 2011 collection Core Samples from the World was an NBCC and Pulitzer Prize finalist for poetry). He is the editor of Alice Iris Red Horse, New Directions’ upcoming collection of poetry by Yoshimasu Gozo.
Yoshimasu Gozo, born in Tokyo, has given performances worldwide, and has received many literary and cultural awards, including the Takami Jun Prize, the Rekitei Prize, the Purple Ribbon, and the 50th Mainichi Art Award for Poetry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Celebration of Julio Cortázar</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/a-celebration-of-julio-cort-zar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 14:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/a-celebration-of-julio-cort-zar/</guid>
      <description>Green Apple Books in San Francisco will be joined by City Lights and the Center for the Art of Translation for a celebration of the legendary Argentine writer Julio Cortázar. Translator Stephen Kessler and special guests will discuss Cortázar&amp;rsquo;s life and read selections from his work.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/0l9MBo_KLffUL0D4OilJ9KvWtKungALsVzWRHwfLXGC7Xn15j7F2q6AnF5xqRTpdHh6vqd2VQe644WB0dokL_OZkcqAqRA=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1471620770858/JC.jpg) Julio Cortázar was an Argentine novelist, short story writer, and essayist. Known as one of the founders of the Latin American Boom, Cortázar influenced an entire generation of Spanish-speaking readers and writers in the Americas and Europe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sylvia Legris and Eliot Weinberger at Book Culture</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/sylvia-legris-and-eliot-weinberger-at-book-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 14:28:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/sylvia-legris-and-eliot-weinberger-at-book-culture/</guid>
      <description>Please join poet Sylvia Legris and essayist and translator Eliot Weinberger for an evening of reading and conversation at Book Culture, in celebration of their latest releases with New Directions.
Sylvia Legris’ latest poetry collection is The Hideous Hidden (Forthcoming from New Directions). Her collection Nerve Squall won both the 2006 Griffin Poetry Prize and the 2006 Pat Lowther Award. Her poems have appeared in many publications, including The New Yorker, Granta, Poetry, and Conjunctions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sylvia Legris at The Winnipeg International Writers Festival</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/sylvia-legris-at-the-winnipeg-international-writers-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 17:36:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/sylvia-legris-at-the-winnipeg-international-writers-festival/</guid>
      <description>Sylvia Legris will be featured along with Jason Stefanik, Lori Cayer, Pamela Mordecai and Susan Holbrook at Thin Air 2016&amp;rsquo;s Mainstage Poetry Bash, as part of the events of the Winnipeg International Writers Festival. Her latest poetry collection, The Hideous Hidden, will be published by New Directions in September. Her earlier work, Nerve Squall, won both the 2006 Griffin Poetry Prize and the 2006 Pat Lowther Award. Legris&amp;rsquo;s poems have appeared in many publications, including The New Yorker, Granta, Poetry, and Conjunctions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Omnidawn Showcase featuring Rosmaire Waldrop</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/omnidawn-showcase-featuring-rosmaire-waldrop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 16:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/omnidawn-showcase-featuring-rosmaire-waldrop/</guid>
      <description>Join Rosmarie Waldrop at Poets House for the Omnidawn Showcase. The evening will feature brief readings by fifteen poets published by Omnidawn.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/I84hlCFl-YXBsnK_XlOpgNTdJKU9UMe0uGnZkVhRkZQI0fH01NwuJDY18yF-q52gVuXak-fB9SZ0S62jGRfG-dgcA6A=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1470325911341/Waldrop.jpg) Rosmarie Waldrop was born in Germany in 1935, and immigrated into the US in 1958. She has a Ph.D. in Comparative Literature from the University of Michigan and has taught at Wesleyan, Tufts, and Brown Universities. She lives in Providence, Rhode Island, with Keith Waldrop (with whom she also co-edits Burning Deck Press).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keith and Rosmarie Waldrop at The Poetry Project</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/keith-and-rosmarie-waldrop-at-the-poetry-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 16:06:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/keith-and-rosmarie-waldrop-at-the-poetry-project/</guid>
      <description>Join Keith and Rosmarie Waldrop for an evening of reading at The Poetry Project.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/Kak-BNRaqumduSbyHmkxByVG_7Wbv4uYxLhHhSOlzcYDSs3o_DRY-9C7jdipz039KfXZKzynwJf2tM4Ua9EBBHmIsrPJ=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1470324838366/waldrops.jpg) Rosmarie Waldrop was born in Germany in 1935, and immigrated into the US in 1958. She has a Ph.D. in Comparative Literature from the University of Michigan and has taught at Wesleyan, Tufts, and Brown Universities. She lives in Providence, Rhode Island, with Keith Waldrop (with whom she also co-edits Burning Deck Press).
She has received awards or fellowships from the NEA, the Fund for Poetry, the Howard Foundation, the DAAD Berlin Artists’ Program, the Foundation of Contemporary Arts, and a Lila Wallace-Reader’s Digest Writers’ Award.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eliot Weinberger and Justin Taylor at Powell&#39;s, Portland</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/eliot-weinberger-and-justin-taylor-at-powells-portland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 16:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/eliot-weinberger-and-justin-taylor-at-powells-portland/</guid>
      <description>Writer, essayist, editor, and translator Eliot Weinberger reads from his latest essay collection, The Ghosts of Birds. Weinberger will be joined in conversation by Justin Taylor, author of Flings and Everything Here Is the Best Thing Ever.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-20FiXWqbGqcqQbjaQsrjKIPKC29ML9T0mXF_odaddCUoezMF1TnpJytZ0GEHTwE0h6wEdVSfbGbrVC6hIxSQtsuWTo=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1476716694303/Eliot%20Weinberger_select_6656.ND.jpg) &amp;ldquo;His essays are dense collages of magical facts that make me ecstatic every time I read them.&amp;rdquo; —Sam Anderson, The New York Times</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harvard Poetry Reading with Keith and Rosmarie Waldrop</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/harvard-poetry-reading-with-keith-and-rosmarie-waldrop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 15:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/harvard-poetry-reading-with-keith-and-rosmarie-waldrop/</guid>
      <description>Join Keith and Rosmarie Waldrop for an evening of poetry at the Houghton Library.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/Slhy0IoziyYVj29YVcYV7prROz_0mubvkSQYuKIpLfGmXlqp0hjwCHXlGVdfZgYsRkKVyMwYR5ZEmCL9ORC47yCCctI=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1470325938942/waldrops.jpg) Rosmarie Waldrop was born in Germany in 1935, and immigrated into the US in 1958. She has a Ph.D. in Comparative Literature from the University of Michigan and has taught at Wesleyan, Tufts, and Brown Universities. She lives in Providence, Rhode Island, with Keith Waldrop (with whom she also co-edits Burning Deck Press).
She has received awards or fellowships from the NEA, the Fund for Poetry, the Howard Foundation, the DAAD Berlin Artists’ Program, the Foundation of Contemporary Arts, and a Lila Wallace-Reader’s Digest Writers’ Award.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sylvia Legris and Will Alexander at Poets House</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/sylvia-legris-and-will-alexander-at-poets-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 16:06:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/sylvia-legris-and-will-alexander-at-poets-house/</guid>
      <description>On the occasion of the publication of The Hideous Hidden, please join Sylvia Legris and Will Alexander for an evening of reading and conversation at Poets House in New York.
In her first full-length collection published in the United States, Sylvia Legris probes and peels, carves and cleaves, amputates and dissects, to reveal the poetic potential of human and animal anatomy.
Starting with the Greek writings of Hippocrates and the Latin language of medicine, and drawing from Leonardo da Vinci’s Anatomical Manuscripts, the dermatologist Robert Willan’s On Cutaneous Diseases (1808), and Baudelaire’s The Flowers of Evil, Legris infuses each poem with unique rhythms that roll off the tongue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ND at the Brooklyn Book Festival: Horacio Castellanos Moya and John Keene</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/nd-at-the-brooklyn-book-festival-horacio-castellanos-moya-and-john-keene/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/nd-at-the-brooklyn-book-festival-horacio-castellanos-moya-and-john-keene/</guid>
      <description>New Directions will be tabling at booth 331 all day, and we are presenting two events:
10 am: &amp;ldquo;Inventing History in New Fiction presented by Community Bookstore&amp;rdquo;: John Keene, Susan Daitch, and Jeremy Davies. Moderated by Christian Lorentzen.
Whether inventing the past from scratch or rewriting its particulars, the avant-garde has long used history as a stage of fruitful experimentation. Contemporary writers are finding new ways to explore a diverse range of topics—from memory and revision to the anecdote and apocrypha—against the backdrop of American and world histories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sylvia Legris at The Word on the Street Saskatoon book festival</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/sylvia-legris-at-the-word-on-the-street-saskatoon-book-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 20:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/sylvia-legris-at-the-word-on-the-street-saskatoon-book-festival/</guid>
      <description>Poet Sylvia Legris will be appearing at The Word on the Street, Canada&amp;rsquo;s largest free book festival. Her latest poetry collection, The Hideous Hidden, will be published by New Directions in September. Her earlier work, Nerve Squall, won both the 2006 Griffin Poetry Prize and the 2006 Pat Lowther Award. Legris&amp;rsquo;s poems have appeared in many publications, including The New Yorker, Granta, Poetry, and Conjunctions. She lives in Saskatoon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Envelope Poems at Picture Room</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/envelope-poems-at-picture-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 20:23:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/envelope-poems-at-picture-room/</guid>
      <description>A celebration of Envelope Poems by Emily Dickinson—our gorgeous copublication with Christine Burgin—in McNally Jackson&amp;rsquo;s beautiful Picture Room space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eliot Weinberger &amp; Stephen Sparks at Green Apple Books on the Park</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/eliot-weinberger-stephen-sparks-at-green-apple-books-on-the-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 20:19:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/eliot-weinberger-stephen-sparks-at-green-apple-books-on-the-park/</guid>
      <description>Green Apple&amp;rsquo;s Stephen Sparks talks with essayist and translator Eliot Weinberger about his new collection,The Ghosts of Birds.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/GLNGUVW8TubeuKTYBKYGku7tNYmae1WL1OVcwO84FdSTB43JKt0iK9d-oul6_3KnD0xFDHQYnczmSLY37_m1AxmXGUo0=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1476716781277/Eliot%20Weinberger_select_6656.ND.jpg) Praise for Eliot Weinberger:
&amp;ldquo;One remains in silent amazement: How does he find these stories? How does he know everything?&amp;rdquo; —Die Zeit
&amp;ldquo;His essays are dense collages of magical facts that make me ecstatic every time I read them.&amp;rdquo; —Sam Anderson, The New York Times
&amp;ldquo;As is often the case with brilliant writers, an Eliot Weinberger sentence cannot be mistaken for that of anyone else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2016 Small Press Flea</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/the-2016-small-press-flea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 14:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/the-2016-small-press-flea/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/7_SETv50ki_hHj3BC4LYlkp8atMtptE8o5g-aevaoNPyGzqOTXHR85D5w-kGipnlN43Embpoe_BIZ8PASXoMVbBp9iG8=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1467382602013/13580487_10154052840259193_1614749911854615786_o.jpg) A summer market with your favorite publishers and magazines. Come say hi to Mieke Chew and Katie Raissian at the New Directions/Stonecutter table!
Presented by BOMB &amp;amp; The Brooklyn Public Library. Rain or shine. (Unless it&amp;rsquo;s an absurd amount of rain.) Featuring: A Public Space Belladonna* Collaborative Birds, LLC Black Sun Lit / Vestiges BOMB Magazine Civil Coping Mechanisms DoubleCross Press Futurepoem George Braziller, Inc. Inpatient Press Litmus Press Monk Books New Directions New York Review Books One Story Persea Books Pioneer Works Printed Matter, Inc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A party for THE LAST SAMURAI at Community Bookstore</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/a-party-for-the-last-samurai-at-community-bookstore/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 18:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/a-party-for-the-last-samurai-at-community-bookstore/</guid>
      <description>The Last Samurai is back! Celebrate its resurrection with Helen DeWitt and New Directions at Community Bookstore, Brooklyn.
Read &amp;ldquo;Seven Ways to Hand-sell a Lost Modern Masterpiece,&amp;rdquo; featuring none other than Community Bookstore&amp;rsquo;s great bookseller, the singular, Hal Hlavinka, in Lithub.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/e9zXVT9763-gbiZdNaVqRYCqj6b3Mzauh6Zl8D0bEj-Hz8ErLJNc6Wu7JqiE-0x5psEI3nO38E-wklCpNvadgq1AoMw=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1466620967900/dewitt_last_samurai_cover_final.jpg) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helen DeWitt and Timo Andres: An Evening of Music and Reading</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/helen-dewitt-and-timo-andres-an-evening-of-music-and-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 16:22:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/helen-dewitt-and-timo-andres-an-evening-of-music-and-reading/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kurosawa&#39;s SEVEN SAMURAI at Metrograph</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/kurosawas-seven-samurai-at-metrograph/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 16:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/kurosawas-seven-samurai-at-metrograph/</guid>
      <description>Please join Helen DeWitt and New Directions for a summer screening of Akira Kurosawa&amp;rsquo;s masterpiece Seven Samurai at Metrograph, New York City.
Tickets on sale through Metrograph.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/DVzNas9wbV9J_FWliruAjWzb0fmEvsJxaX7d5wLWRIsk74PxEqVGwQVEQb88xO9ZjZj6N7m5lswU57sQWYXam06FJoRVqg=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1466611363535/giphy-7.gif) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stories Bookshop &#43; Storytelling Lab Launch with Rivka Galchen and Elisha Cooper</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/stories-bookshop-storytelling-lab-launch-with-rivka-galchen-and-elisha-cooper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 15:53:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/stories-bookshop-storytelling-lab-launch-with-rivka-galchen-and-elisha-cooper/</guid>
      <description>Come celebrate the opening of Stories Bookshop + Storytelling Lab with a special evening of readings! Rivka Galchen and Elisha Cooper will read from their beautiful new books, Little Labors and Falling, respectively. Each story is in its own way a meditation on the profound life-rewiring that is parenthood. This will be a grown-up evening for $35 per person, complete with grown-up refreshments! A night not to be missed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Poetry Party at Community Bookstore on Bastille Day</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/french-poetry-party-at-community-bookstore-on-bastille-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 20:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/french-poetry-party-at-community-bookstore-on-bastille-day/</guid>
      <description>Please join New Directions, NYRB Classics, and Archipelago Books for a French Poetry Party at Community Bookstore this Bastille Day. You&amp;rsquo;ll find us rejoicing in great, lusty, and revelatory French verse in the courtyard on what we hope will be a hot summer&amp;rsquo;s night&amp;hellip;
&amp;ldquo;Bring glory to the love-drunk folks at home!&amp;ldquo;—Charles Baudelaire
&amp;ldquo;Love, something crazy comes to mind: I can&amp;rsquo;t bear being on my best behavior.&amp;ldquo;—Louise Labé
&amp;ldquo;The only reality is Beauty and its only perfect expression is Poetry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bay Area Book Festival presents &#34;The Art of Translation&#34; featuring Katrina Dodson</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/bay-area-book-festival-presents-the-art-of-translation-featuring-katrina-dodson/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 19:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/bay-area-book-festival-presents-the-art-of-translation-featuring-katrina-dodson/</guid>
      <description>Translators alchemize foreign masterworks by harnessing the potential of language. This session explores the nuanced art of translation from the point of view of four of its most devoted practitioners: Katrina Dodson, Amara Lakhous, Jung Young-Moon, and Idra Novey. Moderated by Michael Holtmann, director of the Center for the Art of Translation.
Sponsored by the Center for the Art of Translation, the Italian Cultural Institute in San Francisco, and LTI Korea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Triple Canopy presents &#34;Ecstatic Prose&#34; w/ Rivka Galchen, Hilton Als, Lynne Tillman, and more! </title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/triple-canopy-presents-ecstatic-prose-w-rivka-galchen-hilton-als-lynne-tillman-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 16:38:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/triple-canopy-presents-ecstatic-prose-w-rivka-galchen-hilton-als-lynne-tillman-and-more/</guid>
      <description>Please join Triple Canopy for a day-long series of conversations on the state of literary genre and contemporary prose. Writers Hilton Als, Andrew Durbin, Rivka Galchen, Tan Lin, Sukhdev Sandhu, Christine Smallwood, Jonathan Sturgeon, and Lynne Tillman will participate in a trio of discussions on criticism, style, and autofiction, convened by Triple Canopy editors Lucy Ives and Sarah Resnick.
1:00—2:00 p.m., On Criticism Where and how does criticism find its place?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delmore Schwartz PSA reading and conversation with Adam Kirsch and Craig Morgan Teicher</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/delmore-schwartz-psa-reading-and-conversation-with-adam-kirsch-and-craig-morgan-teicher/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 14:11:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/delmore-schwartz-psa-reading-and-conversation-with-adam-kirsch-and-craig-morgan-teicher/</guid>
      <description>With much of Delmore Schwartz&amp;rsquo;s work out of print for decades,Once and For All: The Best of Delmore Schwartz restores a missing chapter in the history of twentieth-century American literature. Join us for a reading and conversation with Craig Morgan Teicher, the editor of the Once and For All, and fellow Schwartz admirer, Adam Kirsch.
Craig Morgan Teicher is the author of several books of poems and prose, most recently To Keep Love Blurry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edith Grossman: Making Translation Matter at Instituto Cervantes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/edith-grossman-making-translation-matter-at-instituto-cervantes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 14:36:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/edith-grossman-making-translation-matter-at-instituto-cervantes/</guid>
      <description>The Instituto Cervantes New York and the PEN America Foundation co-present this event honoring Edith Grossman on the occasion of her 80th birthday.
One of the most celebrated literary translators in our times, Grossman has been praised for her translations of work by Gabriel García Márquez, Carlos Fuentes, Antonio Muñoz Molina, Sor Juana Inés de la Cruz and many others. Her acclaimed 2003 translation of Cervantes’ Don Quixote is already considered a classic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Directions 80th Birthday Party </title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/new-directions-80th-birthday-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 21:02:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/new-directions-80th-birthday-party/</guid>
      <description>Please come and raise a glass to eighty years of New Directions Publishing at Greenlight Bookstore. We celebrate with micro readings by New Directions greats, Anne Carson, László Krasznahorkai, Rivka Galchen, John Keene, Bernadette Mayer, and Eliot Weinberger! Drinks and merriment to follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benjamin Moser on Clarice Lispector</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/benjamin-moser-on-clarice-lispector/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 16:52:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/benjamin-moser-on-clarice-lispector/</guid>
      <description>In a trio of events, Benjamin Moser, acclaimed author of _Why This World_: A Biography of Clarice Lispector, a finalist for the National Book Critics&amp;rsquo; Circle Award, and editor of Lispector for New Directions, will discuss the work and life of Clarice Lispector and his ongoing project to re-publish the Brazilian author.
Tuesday, April 5. 6PM: Harvard Faculty of Arts and Sciences presents &amp;ldquo;Clarice Lispector&amp;rsquo;s American Dream&amp;rdquo;: A Conversation with Benjamin Moser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Night of Literature, Friends, and Drinks featuring Kareem James Abu-Zeid at Churchill&#39;s Office </title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/a-night-of-literature-friends-and-drinks-featuring-kareem-james-abu-zeid-at-churchills-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 15:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/a-night-of-literature-friends-and-drinks-featuring-kareem-james-abu-zeid-at-churchills-office/</guid>
      <description>Two Lines hosts an intimate, glamorous evening of literature at the private, wood-lined The Office, recently named one of 7x7s Best Private Dining Rooms in San Francisco.
The night will include music, mingling, snacks, live readings from Issues 23 and 24 of Two Lines, and a few other surprises. Translator Kareem James Abu-Zeid will be among those reading.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/1Rskg89o3nosfkW9GLAj7L7acpHf4ZDPHeEr1pfLc1sSTtdVUKysNr1UELCmEFtb_4TmnSooi2nRDMWL5vT0y3vlgoa7=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1458743956852/Abu-Zeid.jpg) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nathaniel Mackey at The Poetry Project</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/nathaniel-mackey-at-the-poetry-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 16:12:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/nathaniel-mackey-at-the-poetry-project/</guid>
      <description>This reading featuring award-winning poet Nathaniel Mackey is a co-presentation with The Institute for Research on the African Diaspora in the Americas and the Caribbean (IRADAC) at the CUNY Graduate Center.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patti Smith: Eighteen Stations </title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/patti-smith-eighteen-stations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 21:44:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/patti-smith-eighteen-stations/</guid>
      <description>Robert Miller Gallery presents Eighteen Stations, a special project by Patti Smith.
Eighteen Stations revolves around the world of M Train, Smith’s bestselling book released in 2015. M Train chronicles, as Smith describes, “a roadmap to my life,” as told from the seats of the cafés and dwellings she has worked from globally. Reflecting the themes and sensibility of the book, Eighteen Stations is a meditation on the act of artistic creation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nicola Gardini at Bard College </title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/nicola-gardini-at-bard-college/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 20:17:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/nicola-gardini-at-bard-college/</guid>
      <description>Nicola Gardini is Professor of Italian and Comparative Literature at Oxford and the author of numerous scholarly and creative works, including the recent Lacuna (Einaudi, 2014). He will speak about his novel Lost Words (New Directions, 2015), a translation by Michael Moore of Le parole perdute di Amelia Lynd (Feltrinelli, 2012), winner of both the Viareggio Prize and Zerilli Marimò/City of Rome Prize.
Gardini will be introduced by Professor Franco Baldasso and in conversation with Professor Joe Luzzi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nicola Gardini and Michael Moore at NYU Casa Italiana </title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/nicola-gardini-and-michael-moore-at-nyu-casa-italiana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 20:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/nicola-gardini-and-michael-moore-at-nyu-casa-italiana/</guid>
      <description>Author Nicola Gardini and translator Michael Moore present Gardini&amp;rsquo;s latest novel, Lost Words, at NYU&amp;rsquo;s Casa Italiana, in a discussion moderated by Michael Wyatt.
Nicola Gardini lives in Oxford and Milan. Lost Words was awarded the Viareggio Prize and the Zerilli-Marimò/City of Rome Prize. A Fellow of Keble College, Oxford, Gardini teaches Italian literature.
The chair of the PEN/Heim Translation Award, Michael F. Moore, has recently translated Live Bait by Fabio Genovesi and Agostino by Alberto Moravia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Evening with the Translators of Elena Ferrante and Roberto Bolaño</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/an-evening-with-the-translators-of-elena-ferrante-and-roberto-bola-o/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 17:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/an-evening-with-the-translators-of-elena-ferrante-and-roberto-bola-o/</guid>
      <description>Literary translation journal Asymptote (www.asymptotejournal.com) celebrates its fifth anniversary with a reading and panel discussion featuring star translators Ann Goldstein and Natasha Wimmer. Novelist Frederic Tuten joins as host and moderator of the discussion, to be followed by audience Q&amp;amp;A and a reception. Asymptote, winner of the 2015 London Book Fair&amp;rsquo;s International Literary Translation Initiative Award, has published work from 100 countries and a total of 77 languages to date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Reading and Conversation with Bernadette Mayer at Columbia University</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/a-reading-and-conversation-with-bernadette-mayer-at-columbia-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 16:21:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/a-reading-and-conversation-with-bernadette-mayer-at-columbia-university/</guid>
      <description>Bernadette Mayer will be reading from her newly released Sonnets (Tender Buttons Press, 2015).
Mayer is the author of over 27 collections, including The Helens of Troy (2013), The Formal Field of Kissing (1990) and Eating The Colors Of A Lineup Of Words: The Early Books of Bernadette Mayer (2015), as well as countless chapbooks and artist-books. She has received grants from The Guggenheim Foundation, National Endowment for the Arts and the Foundation for Contemporary Arts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bernadette Mayer at University of Chicago</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/bernadette-mayer-at-university-of-chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 15:16:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/bernadette-mayer-at-university-of-chicago/</guid>
      <description>Bernadette Mayer, a major influence in the contemporary poetry scene for over four decades, reads from her work. The recipient of the 2014 Shelley Memorial Award from the Poetry Society of America, Mayer is the author of over 27 collections, as well as countless chapbooks and artist-books. Presented by the University of Chicago Library and the Program in Poetry and Poetics
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/7MYfUtCPYwI1-xdGQ89UUU6r89Bz71dCWHdbeOEDhS9gasxAvlbm6u6COPIDtwfWNYahgdQNPecmln2IHRinklm5q2kO=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1456931656211/Mayer_Bernadette600.jpg) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bridge Series: Editing </title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/the-bridge-series-editing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 19:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/the-bridge-series-editing/</guid>
      <description>Presented in partnership with The Bridge and the PEN America Translation Committee
How do you edit a translation? Four experienced editors discuss the pleasures and puzzles of working on translations, from dealing with cultural differences to handling “translationese.” Moderator Sal Robinson will be joined by Lexy Bloom, Jeremy Davies, and Declan Spring.
Lexy Bloom is Senior Editor at Vintage and Anchor Books and Senior Culinary Editor at Alfred A. Knopf, imprints of the Knopf Doubleday Publishing Group at Penguin Random House, Inc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memory: Bernadette Mayer at the Poetry Foundation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/memory-bernadette-mayer-at-the-poetry-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 22:12:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/memory-bernadette-mayer-at-the-poetry-foundation/</guid>
      <description>Memory is a poetic audio-visual installation, shown now in its entirety for the first time since its original 1972 exhibition. During July 1971, Mayer took one roll of film each day, resulting in 1,116 photographs displayed in a grid. The photographs are accompanied by six hours of audio narration, created by Mayer as she remembers and circularly ruminates on the images, using them “as taking-off points for digression, filling in the spaces between.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Again, With Feeling: A MoMA PS1 Sunday Session</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/again-with-feeling-a-moma-ps1-sunday-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 22:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/again-with-feeling-a-moma-ps1-sunday-session/</guid>
      <description>The artist-to-artist exchanges in BOMB go beyond simple dialogue to the ideas at the heart of artistic practice. In a Sunday Session celebrating the magazine&amp;rsquo;s 35th anniversary, ten pairs of artists will revisit their original conversations, ranging from: The emotional nitroglycerine Nicole Eisenman finds in David Humphrey&amp;rsquo;s paintings, the aesthetic high Richard Foreman gets from cutting his plays mid-rehearsal, Tom Burr&amp;rsquo;s queering of institutional critique, and Ralph Lemon&amp;rsquo;s spin on racial profiling in the art world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Faithful” Translation: An Interactive Workshop with Kareem James Abu-Zeid</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/faithful-translation-an-interactive-workshop-with-kareem-james-abu-zeid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 22:03:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/faithful-translation-an-interactive-workshop-with-kareem-james-abu-zeid/</guid>
      <description>Kareem Abu-Zeid is an award-winning translator of poets and novelists from across the Arab world. He also works as a freelance translator of German and French texts. In this practical workshop, participants will have a chance to delve into the nitty-gritty of translating poetry across a cultural and linguistic divide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Cross Borders Lightly: A Conversation with Dunya Mikhail and Kareem Abu-Zeid</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/we-cross-borders-lightly-a-conversation-with-dunya-mikhail-and-kareem-abu-zeid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 21:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/we-cross-borders-lightly-a-conversation-with-dunya-mikhail-and-kareem-abu-zeid/</guid>
      <description>Iraqi Poet Dunya Mikhail and translator Kareem Abu-Zeid will hold a public conversation on the translation of Mikhail’s most recent collection of poetry, The Iraqi Nights. They will discuss the creative collaboration between poet and translator, and the challenges of translating between two languages as different as Arabic and English. They will talk about how to consider nuance, cultural context, politics and beauty in the process of translation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kareem Abu-Zeid at Readers Poetry Series</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/kareem-abu-zeid-at-readers-poetry-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 20:25:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/kareem-abu-zeid-at-readers-poetry-series/</guid>
      <description>Kareem Abu-Zeid will read from his new translation, Rabee Jaber’s Confessions, at Readers Bookstore as a part of a series hosted by San Francisco Poet Laureate Jack Hirschman. Kareem Abu-Zeid is an award-winning translator of poets and novelists from across the Arab world, including Najwan Darwish, Tarek Eltayeb, and Dunya Mikhail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anne Carson at 92Y</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/anne-carson-at-92y/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 18:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/anne-carson-at-92y/</guid>
      <description>Join beloved poet Anne Carson at 92Y as she reads from FLOAT, her forthcoming collection of performance pieces and other poetic writing.
“Reading her books is both an exhilarating and a bewildering experience,” writes Charles Simic. “Carson takes risks, subverts literary conventions and plays havoc with our expectations. She is a wonder: an unconventional, often difficult poet with a huge following.”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWP 2016 in Los Angeles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/awp-2016-in-los-angeles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 14:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/awp-2016-in-los-angeles/</guid>
      <description>New Directions is a featured exhibitor at AWP 2016. We will be selling new and forthcoming titles at discounted prices. Visit Mieke Chew and Tynan Kogane at Booth 725.
Featured ND authors and translators, include: John Keene, Kareem Abu-Zeid, Yvette Siegert, Katrina Dodson, Craig Teicher, and Matt Reeck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delmore Schwartz: The Life and Work of an American Writer </title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/delmore-schwartz-the-life-and-work-of-an-american-writer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 21:25:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/delmore-schwartz-the-life-and-work-of-an-american-writer/</guid>
      <description>This AWP Conference panel celebrates the publication of a new selection of Schwartz’s writings (Once and For All, New Directions 2016) and features talks and readings from Schwartz’s body of work from poetry and fiction writers who owe him a debt.
Delmore Schwartz was an early darling of the generation of American writers that emerged in the 1940s, a pioneer of confessional poetry and Jewish American fiction. His own long descent into mental illness and substance abuse, as well as changing tastes, left his legacy in disarray.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poetry Reading with Mei-Mei Berssenbrugge and Leopoldine Core at Dominique Lévy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/poetry-reading-with-mei-mei-berssenbrugge-and-leopoldine-core-at-dominique-l-vy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 18:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/poetry-reading-with-mei-mei-berssenbrugge-and-leopoldine-core-at-dominique-l-vy/</guid>
      <description>Dominique Lévy Gallery hosts poets Mei-Mei Berssenbrugge and Leopoldine Core for reading and discussion. [](https://www.facebook.com/dominiquelevygallery/)
Contemporary poet Mei-Mei Berssenbrugge will read new poems, including &amp;ldquo;Star Being,&amp;rdquo; commissioned for the exhibition catalogue for &amp;lsquo;Drawing Then: Innovation and Influence in American Drawings of the Sixties.&amp;rsquo; Leopoldine Core joins Berssenbrugge in dialogue, reading recent work, including poems from her newest poetry collection, &amp;lsquo;Veronica Bench&amp;rsquo; (2015).
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/4J6be_gbEREY-ndiPTM7GVXgBnDYr5RvHpxSVWa9bfEHOeewLWcB2aJ1Iu6yZoN0AHuums6DMXXWmt2_Tx090jds9Jg=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1455732615197/mei-mei-berssenbrugge.jpg) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poor Claudia, Kelsey Street Press, Image Text Ithaca: AWP Offsite Event with John Keene</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/poor-claudia-kelsey-street-press-image-text-ithaca-awp-offsite-event-with-john-keene/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 15:47:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/poor-claudia-kelsey-street-press-image-text-ithaca-awp-offsite-event-with-john-keene/</guid>
      <description>Poor Claudia, Kelsey Street Press, and Image Text Ithaca host a reading at the Poetic Research Bureau in this AWP offsite event. It will feature John Keene, Claire Donato, Sueyeun Juliette Lee, Jamalieh Haley, Greg Purcell, Jennifer Pilch, Mg Roberts, Anna Morrison, Catherine Taylor, Matvei Yankelevich &amp;amp; a new short video by Claudia Rankine.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/QxqBPvR4gKu02B4Jh_MAgEntO_-_AnLbJlXfBPgaMCTN1YTpxW3LffSucX3dwphNalmFkOHQcehHhRnq1Ow1MljsZbe6=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1455723731603/PAzo4iv2VwamhQ24OZYiepifHlhFq0niHG_Iz0NdYPngm4U1gmur1aR5fDMVIF7RZ5E8VAzwMq2exEwxAVwAcnfZJmPo%3Ds750) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stevie Smith: A celebration at the Stella Adler Studio</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/stevie-smith-a-celebration-at-the-stella-adler-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 20:51:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/stevie-smith-a-celebration-at-the-stella-adler-studio/</guid>
      <description>Join the Stella Adler Studio in a celebration of the poet Stevie Smith. The evening will include theatrical readings and a discussion with Will May, the editor of All the Poems.
The reading will be held on the second floor in Studio G
Free and open to the public. &amp;hellip;
Will May is an Associate Professor of English at the University of Southampton, England. His publications include Stevie Smith and Authorship (2010) and Postwar Literature: 1950-1990 (2010).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White Space with John Keene, Tonya Foster, and Tyehimba Jess</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/white-space-with-john-keene-tonya-foster-and-tyehimba-jess/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 21:13:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/white-space-with-john-keene-tonya-foster-and-tyehimba-jess/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bernadette Mayer at Small Traffic Press</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/bernadette-mayer-at-small-traffic-press/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 21:58:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/bernadette-mayer-at-small-traffic-press/</guid>
      <description>Small Press Traffic hosts poet Bernadette Mayer for a public reading and conversation.
Since 1974 Small Press Traffic (SPT) has been at the heart of the San Francisco Bay Area innovative writing scene, bringing together authors, readers, educators, small presses, and community members through talks, readings, workshops, and performances.
Bernadette Mayer was born in Brooklyn, New York, and has spent most of her life in New York City. Her collections of poetry include Midwinter Day (1982, 1999), A Bernadette Mayer Reader (1992), The Desire of Mothers to Please Others in Letters (1994), Another Smashed Pinecone (1998), Poetry State Forest (2008), and the forthcoming Works and Days (2016).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Afternoon with Bernadette Mayer at Poets House</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/an-afternoon-with-bernadette-mayer-at-poets-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 15:38:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/an-afternoon-with-bernadette-mayer-at-poets-house/</guid>
      <description>Poets House hosts Bernadette Mayer for an afternoon of reading and conversation. She is the author of more than twenty collections of poetry including Poetry State Forest (2008) and her forthcoming collection, Works and Days.
This reading will feature special introductions by Michael Ruby andSam Truitt, co-editors of Eating the Colors of a Lineup of Words: The Collected Early Books of Bernadette Mayer (2015).
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/MqpbN146WtSJQuGQiGMKnfvm91cxCqWz6h_Kp7tqs3AdN_Avbh5mcHDP9Gc0n17NaHCgbxk__LGUKxvFsMJzlaYFa9xwZg=s600)](/webhook-uploads/1455227618647/Bernadette%20Mayer%20Player%20Card%20A.png) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bernadette Mayer - Holloway Poetry Reading</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/bernadette-mayer-holloway-poetry-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 21:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/bernadette-mayer-holloway-poetry-reading/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/kyc30cDpdMx4BDAoBiFX32r5Hmltv0ZOmIOkZhtknufd9Svi3wnEaw8USU-Xw794DNV6dE6vEmBdb9uqeijqKb2-y0o=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1455056443917/Bernadette%20Mayer%20Player%20Card%20A.png) UC Berkeley&amp;rsquo;s English department presents Bernadette Mayer as part of its Holloway Reading Series. Mayer, an avant-garde writer and visual artist, will be joined by Christian Nagler (a graduate student at Berkeley). The event is free and open to the public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warhol by the Book at the Morgan Library and Museum</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/warhol-by-the-book-at-the-morgan-library-and-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 15:32:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/warhol-by-the-book-at-the-morgan-library-and-museum/</guid>
      <description>Andy Warhol’s fascination with publishing and the art of the book was lifelong—rooted in his artistic training as a college student and early career in advertising, fashion, and commercial illustration. For close to forty years, books were a touchstone for Warhol—a medium to which he returned again and again as a platform for his unparalleled creativity. He contributed to more than eighty projects for books and left traces behind of dozens of others that were never realized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Voices Salon with Valerie Miles on Enrique Vila-Matas</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/two-voices-salon-with-valerie-miles-on-enrique-vila-matas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 17:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/two-voices-salon-with-valerie-miles-on-enrique-vila-matas/</guid>
      <description>Join Two Lines on Thursday, February 11 for the first salon of 2016, featuring powerhouse editor and translator Valerie Miles, who will be in conversation with Two Lines Press’s Scott Esposito via Skype.
Miles will be discussing her newly translated novella Because She Never Asked by the Spanish writer Enrique Vila-Matas. Called “Spain’s most significant contemporary literary figure” by The New Yorker, Vila-Matas excels in creating witty fictions out of his real life that deconstruct the act of writing and make us reconsider many of the key figures of literature and cinema of the 20th century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rivka Galchen, Francisco Goldman, and Idra Novey at the Center for Fiction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/rivka-galchen-francisco-goldman-and-idra-novey-at-the-center-for-fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 15:16:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/rivka-galchen-francisco-goldman-and-idra-novey-at-the-center-for-fiction/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/hk-NnlQe9xYC1imoEMQiaS2sa7oxZLKQinQ_pj_RtxDD6bjyeLwukE-mLtJyTwctpQCqNIhSVXdIeJaHRCPrHRItiUgI=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1454944511545/Center%20for%20Fiction%20with%20Rvka.jpg) Rivka Galchen, Francisco Goldman, and Idra Novey will discuss the challenges and benefits of moving between fiction and other genres and how that movement can lead to new ways of thinking about the novel as a form. Each will read from their most recent books and talk about writing fiction while also working on essays, journalism, poetry, and translation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pegasus Books Celebrates Robert Lax</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/pegasus-books-celebrates-robert-lax/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 21:08:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/pegasus-books-celebrates-robert-lax/</guid>
      <description>Pegasus Books hosts an evening of reading and discussion with Michael McGregor, author of Pure Act: The Uncommon Life of Robert Lax. McGregor&amp;rsquo;s new biography is a thoughtful study of a man whose joyful and influential poetry earned him praise as &amp;ldquo;one of America’s greatest experimental poets.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;McGregor eloquently offers the definitive biography of a too often forgotten figure who influenced a number of writers and crafted spirituality out of his deep commitment to love, poverty, and justice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pure Act: The Uncommon Life of Robert Lax</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/pure-act-the-uncommon-life-of-robert-lax/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 20:08:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/pure-act-the-uncommon-life-of-robert-lax/</guid>
      <description>City Lights Books celebrates the release of _Pure Act: The Uncommon Life of Robert La_x. Michael McGregor, author of this new outstanding biography, will be joined by John Beer (former literary assistant and editor of Lax) and S.T. Georgiou (author of In the Beginning Was Love: Contemplative Words of Robert Lax) for an evening of readings and discussion.
&amp;ldquo;Pure Act is much more than a biography. It&amp;rsquo;s a real and full and personal meditation on life, and on what a life is for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Segue Reading Series: Dawn Lundy Martin &amp; Rosmarie Waldrop</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/segue-reading-series-dawn-lundy-martin-rosmarie-waldrop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 19:58:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/segue-reading-series-dawn-lundy-martin-rosmarie-waldrop/</guid>
      <description>Segue hosts the experimental reading series Segue@Zinc, a continuation of the legendary series that has run continuously for 25 years. This installment features readings by poets Rosmarie Waldrop and Dawn Lundy Martin.
Gap Gardening: Selected Poems is forthcoming from New Directions in 2016. She is the author of two novels, a memoir, and a book of essays, among many books. She translates German and French poetry and co-edits Burning Deck books with Keith Waldrop in Providence RI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Keene, 2016 DuPlessis Lecture in Poetry &amp; Poetics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/john-keene-2016-duplessis-lecture-in-poetry-poetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 19:26:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/john-keene-2016-duplessis-lecture-in-poetry-poetics/</guid>
      <description>Temple University&amp;rsquo;s Creative Writing MFA Program hosts author John Keene for a reading and discussion of his work.
John Keene is the author of the novel Annotations (New Directions); the art-poetry collection Seismosis (1913 Press) with artist Christopher Stackhouse; and the short fiction collection Counternarratives (New Directions), which has been named to &amp;ldquo;Best Fiction of 2015&amp;rdquo; lists by New York Magazine, Vanity Fair, LitHub, Flavorwire, and other publications. He has also published a translation of Brazilian author Hilda Hilst’s novel Letters from a Seducer (Nightboat Books / A Bolha Editora), and has exhibited his artwork in Brooklyn and Berlin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings in Contemporary Poetry: Keith and Rosmarie Waldrop </title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/readings-in-contemporary-poetry-keith-and-rosmarie-waldrop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 19:04:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/readings-in-contemporary-poetry-keith-and-rosmarie-waldrop/</guid>
      <description>Dia’s monthly Readings in Contemporary Poetry series, curated by poet and author Vincent Katz, highlights commonalities between poets and puts their diverse voices in conversation with one another.
Rosmarie Waldrop’s Gap Gardening: Selected Poems is forthcoming from New Directions in spring 2016. She is the author of two novels, a memoir, and a book of essays, among many books. She translates German and French poetry and co-edits Burning Deck books with Keith Waldrop in Providence, RI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thomas Merton: The Glory of the World</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/thomas-merton-the-glory-of-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 22:08:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/thomas-merton-the-glory-of-the-world/</guid>
      <description>BAM and Knight Blanc present The Glory of the World, a play celebrating the centennial of Thomas Merton. Speeches, fights, intoxication, and spiritual reflection ensue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IN TRANSLATION: An Evening with Katrina Dodson</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/in-translation-an-evening-with-katrina-dodson/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 21:36:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/in-translation-an-evening-with-katrina-dodson/</guid>
      <description>Join Katrina Dodson, translator of Clarice Lispector&amp;rsquo;s The Complete Stories (one of the __New York Times’ 100 Notable Books of 2015), for part of a reading &amp;amp; lecture series focusing on literature in translation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLARICE LISPECTOR: Katrina Dodson with writer Lidia Yuknavitch</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/clarice-lispector-katrina-dodson-with-writer-lidia-yuknavitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 20:56:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/clarice-lispector-katrina-dodson-with-writer-lidia-yuknavitch/</guid>
      <description>Join Powell&amp;rsquo;s Books for a celebration of Clarice Lispector with Katrina Dodson, translator of Lispector&amp;rsquo;s The Complete Stories (one of the _New York Times_’ 100 Notable Books of 2015). Dodson will be joined by Lidia Yuknavitch, author of The Small Backs of Children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLARICE LISPECTOR: Katrina Dodson at Elliott Bay, Seattle</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/clarice-lispector-katrina-dodson-at-elliott-bay-seattle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 20:23:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/clarice-lispector-katrina-dodson-at-elliott-bay-seattle/</guid>
      <description>Join Elliott Bay Book Company for an evening of reading and discussion of Clarice Lispector with Katrina Dodson (translator of Lispector&amp;rsquo;s The Complete Stories). &amp;ldquo;Clarice Lispector has a diamond-hard intelligence, a visionary instinct, and a sense of humor that veered from naíf wonder to wicked comedy…she attempts to capture what it is to think our existence as we are in it - in the ‘marvelous scandal,’ as Lispector puts it, of life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Irish Repertory Theatre Presents A Child&#39;s Christmas in Wales </title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/the-irish-repertory-theatre-presents-a-childs-christmas-in-wales/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 21:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/the-irish-repertory-theatre-presents-a-childs-christmas-in-wales/</guid>
      <description>Irish Repertory Theatre presents A Child&amp;rsquo;s Christmas in Wales by Dylan Thomas, directed by Charlotte Moore with musical direction by Mark Hartman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BAM presents Rimbaud in New York</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/bam-presents-rimbaud-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 21:47:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/bam-presents-rimbaud-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>“The Poet makes himself into a seer by a long, involved, and logical derangement of all the senses. Every kind of love, of suffering, of madness; he searches himself; he exhausts every possible poison so that only essence remains.”—Arthur Rimbaud
He smoked a clay pipe, stole books, wrote hymns to bodily orifices, and, by the age of 21, had changed the face of literature forever. But then Arthur Rimbaud disappeared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefit for ISSUE Project Room</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/benefit-for-issue-project-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 21:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/benefit-for-issue-project-room/</guid>
      <description>SOLD OUT
A special evening to benefit ISSUE Project Room at their historic 22 Boerum Place theater. Following the completion of our renovation&amp;rsquo;s initial phase, this event offers a unique opportunity to glimpse ISSUE&amp;rsquo;s home before the final stage of construction begins.
Esteemed performance artist and video pioneer Joan Jonas performs excerpts from a recent work. Composer and vocalist GABI is joined by Michael Pisaro to present his composition Tombstones with a live ensemble of acoustic instruments and percussion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vitality of New Forms: Designs by Alvin Lustig and Elaine Lustig Cohen</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/vitality-of-new-forms-designs-by-alvin-lustig-and-elaine-lustig-cohen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 19:08:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/vitality-of-new-forms-designs-by-alvin-lustig-and-elaine-lustig-cohen/</guid>
      <description>Alvin Lustig and Elaine Lustig Cohen are towering figures in American graphic design. Lustig, a beloved teacher and influential critic as well as a polymath designer, advocated an ambitious mission for the discipline, insisting that a true designer could guide public taste toward “the proper expression of the society he lives in.” As head of her own office, Cohen maintained an independence that was rare for women at mid-century. In 1973 she co-founded Ex Libris, a rare book and ephemera shop that played an essential role in the development of design history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hora de Clarice: A Party for Clarice Lispector at 192 Books</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/hora-de-clarice-a-party-for-clarice-lispector-at-192-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 16:22:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/hora-de-clarice-a-party-for-clarice-lispector-at-192-books/</guid>
      <description>Please join New Directions and 192 Books as we raise a glass in honor of Clarice Lispector&amp;rsquo;s birthday. There will be books and bubbly flowing and spirits will be high! It&amp;rsquo;s a lovely chance to reflect on the overwhelming response to The Complete Stories of Clarice Lispector translated by Katrina Dodson and edited by Benjamin Moser.
Hora de Clarice has been running in Brazil for the last five years with simultaneous celebrations in Paris, Madrid, Lisbon, Frankfurt, Buenos Aires, and Mexico City.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Susan Howe &amp; Ben Lerner at 92Y</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/susan-howe-ben-lerner-at-92y/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 21:06:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/susan-howe-ben-lerner-at-92y/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/qj6AqsVDHmT8Z34J1njbd-axBm48COJZEZ0WSqe9O-4eUAYq5PWsaKfxq9os6Z6uhRBJJNeDEmPYXWCbcTeZrB5zaWJJ=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1454948885929/g_040716_howe_lerner.jpg) An evening with two poets also highly regarded for their prose.
“No other poet now writing has Susan Howe’s power to bring together narrative and lyric, scholarship and historical speculation, found text and pure invention,” wrote Marjorie Perloff. Howe’s new essay collection is The Quarry. Ben Lerner has written three books of poetry (most recently Mean Free Path) and two novels (Leaving Atocha Station and 10:04) “A writer of true originality,” wrote Jeffrey Eugenides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Celebration of Robert Lax</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/a-celebration-of-robert-lax/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 17:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/a-celebration-of-robert-lax/</guid>
      <description>Michael N. McGregor and John Beer will read and be interviewed by Paul Martone of Late Night Library during this celebration of the poet Robert Lax.
Admission is Free</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counternarratives: A Fiction and Poetry Reading with John Keene and Paolo Javier</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/counternarratives-a-fiction-and-poetry-reading-with-john-keene-and-paolo-javier/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/counternarratives-a-fiction-and-poetry-reading-with-john-keene-and-paolo-javier/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/xjzFqEAHP1hsR_7wRmmNG_xVdembv3zttCQ8oqwo-JqKSCpBb791dhGzTYaIVaH6GZBFX1xpEmBbwhKyH85LajFlXKcA=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1448035148440/12239586_10156175967150543_2355736256305946105_n.jpg) Counternarratives: A Fiction and Poetry Reading John Keene and Paolo Javier With Listening Center
The Brooklyn Rail @ Industry City In collaboration with Nightboat Books
JOHN KEENE is the author of the novel Annotations (New Directions); the text-art collection Seismosis (1913 Press) with artist Christopher Stackhouse; and the short fiction collection Counternarratives (New Directions). He also translated Brazilian author Hilda Hilst’s novel Letters from a Seducer (Nightboat/A Bolha Editora). He has published his work in a wide array of periodicals and anthologies, and has exhibited his artwork in Brooklyn and Berlin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tilo Steireif’s exhibition of 112 watercolors of Robert Walser&#39;s *The Robber*</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/tilo-steireifs-exhibition-of-112-watercolors-of-robert-walsers-the-robber/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 15:48:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/tilo-steireifs-exhibition-of-112-watercolors-of-robert-walsers-the-robber/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/rgWNqD7h4sD16vKNT3wvOxeNh1b4F3DvsexnBP2a8Uk2sfxEB-8Vi87Be2Nl1hpHJ85W6yRm4dvIW5MsbbeVRlz6u3yT=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1448036459350/csm_Tilo_Raeuber_067_2d464505b5.jpg) Starting the 19th of November, the Robert Walser Center in Bern presents an exhibition on Tilo Steireif’s interpretation of Robert Walser’s novel, The Robber. The Lausanne native depicts his perceptions through a series of 112 watercolor paintings. Published posthumously in 1972, the novel is considered a milestone of modernist literature.
Tilo Steireif produced his subtle yet spectacular interpretation of the novel between 2012 and 2013 in Berlin. It now appears on view to the public for the first time in this new exhibition at the Robert Walser Center.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OMDiosa: John Keene, Eunsong Kim, Jennif(f)er Tamayo</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/omdiosa-john-keene-eunsong-kim-jenniffer-tamayo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 19:54:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/omdiosa-john-keene-eunsong-kim-jenniffer-tamayo/</guid>
      <description>John Keene is the author of the award-winning novel Annotations (New Directions); the art-poetry collection Seismosis (1913 Press) with artist Christopher Stackhouse; and the short fiction collection Counternarratives (New Directions), which has been named to &amp;ldquo;Best Fiction of 2015&amp;rdquo; lists by New York Magazine and Flavorwire, and selected as a &amp;ldquo;top read&amp;rdquo; by Library Journal, Time Out New York, and Washington City Paper. He has also published a translation of Brazilian author Hilda Hilst’s novel _Letters from a Seducer (_Nightboat Books / A Bolha Editora).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bernadette Mayer reading at Columbia University</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/bernadette-mayer-reading-at-columbia-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 17:46:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/bernadette-mayer-reading-at-columbia-university/</guid>
      <description>WRITING | READING AND CONVERSATION
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/Xm7lIA7SYOE_F0EgTnhG3cdeSdNu3M_7rsJYcKCtB71KWH1xYV5MLi0HwyL8KZtu1KshRpQN2GZ5r0CX_iXS45F4CEpA=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1447263320281/EVP_BernadetteMayer.JPG) Bernadette Mayer will be reading from her newly released Sonnets this Thursday at Columbia University.
Mayer is the author of over 27 collections, including The Helens of Troy (2013), The Formal Field of Kissing (1990) and Eating The Colors Of A Lineup Of Words: The Early Books of Bernadette Mayer (2015), as well as countless chapbooks and artist-books. She has received grants from The Guggenheim Foundation, National Endowment for the Arts and the Foundation for Contemporary Arts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Katrina Dodson and Susan Harris discuss Lispector&#39;s Complete Stories</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/katrina-dodson-and-susan-harris-discuss-lispectors-complete-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 15:56:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/katrina-dodson-and-susan-harris-discuss-lispectors-complete-stories/</guid>
      <description>Join Unabridged Bookstore for an evening in celebration of Clarice Lispector with Katrina Dodson, translator of The Complete Stories by Clarice Lispector in coversation with Susan Harris, the editorial director of Words without Borders.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/UltbbBJ3-IRN6YdsiQ9i3DnJNrB_qflKXV2m-sP2KQqj_8e_JwxwywMTpTWIF9zM6iZGz61w3e-ZF-oblXVvlljWMZXl=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1447084763729/CL_pc01env08_foto017.jpg) Light refreshments will be served.
Susan Harris is the editorial director of Words without Borders (www.wordswithoutborders.org) and the coeditor with Ilya Kaminsky of The Ecco Book of International Poetry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Katrina Dodson and Andrew Ervin on Clarice Lispector</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/katrina-dodson-and-andrew-ervin-on-clarice-lispector/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 14:38:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/katrina-dodson-and-andrew-ervin-on-clarice-lispector/</guid>
      <description>Katrina Dodson, translator of Clarice Lispector&amp;rsquo;s Complete Stories (New Directions) and Andrew Ervin (Burning Down George Orwell&amp;rsquo;s House) talk about Dodson&amp;rsquo;s new translation of Lispector&amp;rsquo;s short stories.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/U-7PYgY4FlTOvs54_VjuohckicExFwr8QT4sE6ddbEkRtpNHsFB279HLnJgZNg_1vUgqYFcoi5vOJBOVKjJkQjy-v_pz=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1447079940160/CL017.jpg) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>László Krasznahorkai &amp; Salman Rushdie at 92Y</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/l-szl--krasznahorkai-salman-rushdie-at-92y/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 20:11:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/l-szl--krasznahorkai-salman-rushdie-at-92y/</guid>
      <description>A rare US appearance by László Krasznahorkai—the “contemporary Hungarian master of apocalypse,” wrote Susan Sontag. Winner of this year’s Man Booker International Prize, Krasznahorkai is author of The Melancholy of Resistance, Satantango and Seiobo There Below. His new collection of nonfiction is Destruction and Sorrow Beneath the Heavens: Reportage.
He is joined by one of his biggest local admirers, Salman Rushdie, whose new novel, Two Years, Eight Months and Twenty-Eight Nights, is set in a New York of the near future made strange after a massive storm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Library Symposium at Poets House</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/library-symposium-at-poets-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 17:21:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/library-symposium-at-poets-house/</guid>
      <description>An afternoon spent in silence? A-Z? The cosmic order of Borges&amp;rsquo; library of the imagination? Whatever the duration, extent, or dimensions of your perfect library, this day-long symposium will delight and inform as it winds through the many roles libraries take on in the community of readers and in the imagination, as collection, as shared intellectual and physical space, and as the symbol of shared knowledge.
• 12:00pm: Collections, Curators, and Community: A Conversation with Nancy Kuhl, Shannon Mattern, and Kevin Young</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Celebration of Robert Walser at the NEW MUSEUM</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/a-celebration-of-robert-walser-at-the-new-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 16:51:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/a-celebration-of-robert-walser-at-the-new-museum/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/PJporyWY9GgQWtAW6Gmr8_yOc44bmmy-oWkoa5uoH4ziagoILufQvUz_aFEagElkwyGqB68HX9pXjvxiqGgV0GIAKem_5g=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1446137797508/AKG46199.jpg) Translated by Susan Bernofsky, Lydia Davis, and Christopher Middleton, Looking at Pictures presents a little-known facet of the work of the eccentric genius Robert Walser (1878-1956): his writing on art.
Please join the New Museum, Christine Burgin, and New Directions for a celebration of Robert Walser with readings from Susan Bernofsky, Moyra Davey, Josiah McElheny, Nathaniel Weaver, Barbara Epler, and Christine Burgin.
The book launch will be held in the New Museum&amp;rsquo;s Sky Room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BOHUMIL HRABAL: A Celebration and Conversation with Paul Wilson and Christopher Harwood</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/bohumil-hrabal-a-celebration-and-conversation-with-paul-wilson-and-christopher-harwood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 18:53:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/bohumil-hrabal-a-celebration-and-conversation-with-paul-wilson-and-christopher-harwood/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/HQK8QNcEY83wAxWkkMeQW5QGv_0bEzdtFN-KD6WhUIXeLoYZnvn26_TZAWkyeRliR1_aEa15c-Tj3jqRXZRVpZoAPFlc=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1445626392028/MrKafka_LaunchPR2%20for%20site.jpg) New Directions invites you to a celebration of Bohumil Hrabal’s MR. KAFKA AND OTHER TALES FROM THE TIME OF THE CULT
Please join us on Thursday November 5th, at 7:00 pm for a conversation between translator Paul Wilson and Columbia University lecturer in Czech language Christopher Harwood, at the Czech Center of New York. Pilsner will be served.
“Hrabal’s magical stories are comic and human—they are really desires embodied. They inhabit a utopian province, the realm of laughter and tears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scupltures and Monotypes with Amy &amp; Michael McClure</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/scupltures-and-monotypes-with-amy-michael-mcclure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 21:01:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/scupltures-and-monotypes-with-amy-michael-mcclure/</guid>
      <description>Sculpture &amp;amp; Monotypes
by Amy Evans McClure Words by Michael McClure
Special Reception November 7th from 2:00-5:00</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miami Book Fair: City Lights Publishers at 60 with Elaine Katzenberger, Paul Yamazaki, Barbara Epler &amp; David Ulin</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/miami-book-fair-city-lights-publishers-at-60-with-elaine-katzenberger-paul-yamazaki-barbara-epler-david-ulin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 18:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/miami-book-fair-city-lights-publishers-at-60-with-elaine-katzenberger-paul-yamazaki-barbara-epler-david-ulin/</guid>
      <description>From co-founder Lawrence Ferlinghetti’s first book to the new poetry collection of the 2015-16 U.S. Poet Laureate, Juan Felipe Herrera, City Lights has earned its reputation for publishing cutting-edge fiction, poetry, memoirs, literary translations and books on vital social and political issues. Now sixty years old, City Lights is considered one of America’s major alternative presses. Join in this celebration with City Light’s publisher/executive director Elaine Katzenberger, head bookstore buyer Paul Yamazaki, president of New Directions, Barbara Epler; and moderator, _Los Angeles Times_’ book critic David Ulin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2015 Living Writers Series: John Keene</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/fall-2015-living-writers-series-john-keene/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 20:52:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/fall-2015-living-writers-series-john-keene/</guid>
      <description>On October 22nd John Keene, author of Counternarratives will take part in the Living Writers Series at UC Santa Cruz.
Each quarter, the Humanities Division’s Living Writers Series brings visiting authors and poets into UC Santa Cruz classes to give students an in-depth look into the world of the working writer.
This fall, the series will focus on the theme of Creative Work &amp;amp; Critical Play. Creative Work &amp;amp; Critical Play features contemporary writers and artists who mine issues of race, sexuality, gender, and class through several genres and media&amp;ndash;including poetry, fiction, critical prose, performance, sonic and visual art, and memoir.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Heart of the Matter Series with Robyn Creswell and Dunya Mikhail</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/the-heart-of-the-matter-series-with-robyn-creswell-and-dunya-mikhail/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 20:19:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/the-heart-of-the-matter-series-with-robyn-creswell-and-dunya-mikhail/</guid>
      <description>Words of War, Words of Loss.
Poetry has always been central to Arabic cultural expression. Today, it encompasses the whirlwind of events sweeping across the Middle East, serving to mourn tragedy and articulate political fantasies. Robyn Creswell, co-author of The New Yorker article “Why Jihadists Write Poetry,” and Iraqi poet Dunya Mikhail, who fled her country after being put on Sadaam Hussein’s enemies list, discuss poetry as a way to understand contemporary Arab society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paris Review Live: Nathaniel Mackey and Cathy Park Hong at 92 Y</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/paris-review-live-nathaniel-mackey-and-cathy-park-hong-at-92-y/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 15:09:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/paris-review-live-nathaniel-mackey-and-cathy-park-hong-at-92-y/</guid>
      <description>Over the years, the Poetry Center has teamed with The Paris Review to present numerous onstage conversations that have often led to Writers-at-Work interviews appearing in the magazine. In this latest installment, poet Nathaniel Mackey—winner of this year&amp;rsquo;s Bollingen Prize—will read from his work and sit for a conversation with Cathy Park Hong.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/38k0HnZWRrxNoYSBRVAOVZTbZivvQtexI0viGm6YWR_mrw3fRMM5jxfxaPgIqTUAGlufZ919NGTRyBu76V3hhu2jLqaw=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1444144140031/h_mackeynathaniel.jpg) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forum on Religion &amp; Literature: Susan Howe</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/forum-on-religion-literature-susan-howe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 20:22:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/forum-on-religion-literature-susan-howe/</guid>
      <description>When: Thursday, November 12, 2015 3:30 PM - 5:00 PM
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/J163M9lGuwr6Q7QgD8W3JucBUnvp8qIYZ8XosnZZVQhskPEBkM-r4C_uFwfZErFsz5ADLTdjaXC6MN3T-BHnHHnxdJIm=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1443644717248/howebw6flat.tif) Where: Whitney Humanities Center (WALL53), Room 208
53 Wall St., New Haven, CT 06511
Description: ‘faith makes its own forms’: Jonathan Edwards, Wallace Stevens, and Experimental Poetry presented by Susan Howe, followed by moderated discussion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> || CANCELLED || Susan Howe and David Grubbs: Performance Retrospective</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/cancelled-susan-howe-and-david-grubbs-performance-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 15:25:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/cancelled-susan-howe-and-david-grubbs-performance-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>Souls of the Labadie Tract (2007) Frolic Architecture (2009) Tuesday, December 1, 8:00 p.m.
WOODSLIPPERCOUNTERCLATTER (2013) Susan Howe and David Grubbs in conversation Wednesday, December 2, 8:00 p.m.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/asXwvQCwaAGIguS-VnogaSD3GjPZQf6t2k_VmfssWnfGRRakjG56gsdjCcoJmuG0xj38_X5ECIGKMnC0ErFMMkB8BF8w=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1443108160420/large_SusanHowe_DavidGrubbs_WOODSLIPPERCOUNTERCLATTER_C.jpg) The Museum of Modern Art is pleased to host ISSUE Project Room for a two-evening retrospective of collaborative performance works by poet Susan Howe and musician David Grubbs. Author of more than a dozen books of poetry and three of literary criticism, Susan Howe held the Samuel P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghost Politics with Eka Kurniawan and Annie Tucker</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/ghost-politics-with-eka-kurniawan-and-annie-tucker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 17:12:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/ghost-politics-with-eka-kurniawan-and-annie-tucker/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/EsJBa5Mi9KxT-Q6dXDGkFAwuRGmrr0P4RHHch1b_YBxVO4ZsJBP6j0zUwwlaNvJ08pO7IhjcmwYisfp36PXSHrl8H2wX=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1442855489096/respublika.jpg) One of Indonesia’s most prominent novelists, Eka Kurniawan has been likened to Gabriel Garcia Marquez and Toni Morrison and named the successor to Indonesia national novelist Pramaoedya Ananta Toer by none other than Benedict Anderson. Join us to celebrate the English language debut—and a rare stateside appearance—of a great world novelist, sure to join the ranks of Bolano, Ferrante, and Murakami.
When Eka started writing his epic Beauty Is a Wound (New Directions 2015), he had wanted to write about an undead woman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JOHN KEENE at The Pratt Central Library</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/john-keene-at-the-pratt-central-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 18:54:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/john-keene-at-the-pratt-central-library/</guid>
      <description>Hosted by The Ivy Bookshop, award-winning writer John Keene discusses his new experimental story collection, which sheds new light on the American past.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/tMfx7wrTu4U0cZKZ6-qyqntmNpujRfPfij_pWEAjSkIczW-ehRGTRJodsERvdtTAvYUu0EKdVa4rvb6kOemS89U7Jpo=s600)](/webhook-uploads/1442430270559/PAzo4iv2VwamhQ24OZYiepifHlhFq0niHG_Iz0NdYPngm4U1gmur1aR5fDMVIF7RZ5E8VAzwMq2exEwxAVwAcnfZJmPo%3Ds750.jpg) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berkeley Book Chats: Katrina Dodson on THE COMPLETE STORIES</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/berkeley-book-chats-katrina-dodson-on-the-complete-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 16:37:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/berkeley-book-chats-katrina-dodson-on-the-complete-stories/</guid>
      <description>After an introduction by Candace Slater (Spanish and Portuguese), Dodson will speak briefly about translating The Complete Stories and then open the floor for discussion. Dodson’s recent translation of Clarice Lispector’s Complete Stories collects for the first time all 85 short stories by one of Brazil’s most important writers, from Lispector’s first published story in 1939 at the age of 19 to her last written in 1977.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Katrina Dodson reads from THE COMPLETE STORIES at Alley Cat Books</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/katrina-dodson-reads-from-the-complete-stories-at-alley-cat-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 16:28:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/katrina-dodson-reads-from-the-complete-stories-at-alley-cat-books/</guid>
      <description>Hosted by Jane Ciabattari and Grant Faulkner, Katrina Dodson reads from The Complete Stories with the Flash Fiction Collective.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/x1FWLeNE0bDIYDbudWByvYd7Ic6v4NFVwoh7il4P9uwOPa7JOwsRsA28guFIisIMDWUjUXHCv0HNL_d0PU9_1RYIjLcG=s600)](/webhook-uploads/1442334449086/katrina_dodson%20small.tiff) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People of the Cave : Triple Canopy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/the-people-of-the-cave-triple-canopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 18:38:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/the-people-of-the-cave-triple-canopy/</guid>
      <description>With Anna Della Subin, Gini Alhadeff, Omar Berrada, Robyn Creswell, Sukhdev Sandhu, Emily Stokes &amp;amp; Eliot Weinberger.
Writer and editor Anna Della Subin presents a reading of Tawfiq al-Hakim’s 1933 play The People of the Cave as part of Triple Canopy’s The Long Tomorrow issue. The play, based on the legend of the Seven Sleepers of Ephesus, which also appears in the Qur’an, tells the story of three Christian men and a dog who awaken in a cave after fleeing from persecution by their pagan king.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EKA KURNIAWAN &amp; Siddhartha Deb at McNally Jackson</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/eka-kurniawan-siddhartha-deb-at-mcnally-jackson/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 16:25:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/eka-kurniawan-siddhartha-deb-at-mcnally-jackson/</guid>
      <description>Join us to celebrate the English language debut of Indonesia’s rising star Eka Kurniawan. Compulsively readable, Kurniawan’s new novel Beauty Is a Wound combines history, satire, legend and humour, in an epic family tragedy, in which the beautiful Indo prostitute Dewi Ayu and her four daughters are beset by monstrosity. With Siddhartha Deb, author of The Beautiful and the Damned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EKA KURNIAWAN at Green Apple Books on the Park</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/eka-kurniawan-at-green-apple-books-on-the-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 15:58:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/eka-kurniawan-at-green-apple-books-on-the-park/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/wC6Hcd68Ke1h8Sg1AktNuSPIsbv6oXW-6-Q34CpA2PbiobnFtBGDHd_q8hBUUiRBXYdrh5fXJ_M0dKmMLhOtqMTRoug=s600)](/webhook-uploads/1441295851566/kurniawan.tiff) The Center for the Art of Translation presents Eka Kurniawan and translator Annie Tucker in conversation with Olivia Sears.
Considered by many to be Indonesia&amp;rsquo;s greatest novelist, Kurniawan will discuss Beauty Is a Wound (New Directions) and Man Tiger (Verso), both published on the same day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Katrina Dodson presents THE COMPLETE STORIES with Magdalena Edwards</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/katrina-dodson-presents-the-complete-stories-with-magdalena-edwards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 14:25:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/katrina-dodson-presents-the-complete-stories-with-magdalena-edwards/</guid>
      <description>Katrina Dodson is the translator of The Complete Stories by Clarice Lispector. She lives in San Francisco and is finishing a PhD in Comparative Literature at the University of California, Berkeley.
Magdalena Edwards was born in Santiago, Chile, and raised in Chicago, Los Angeles, and Washington, DC. Her thesis on Raúl Zurita&amp;rsquo;s Purgatorio (1979), written while an undergraduate at Harvard, led to a stint with the “Artes &amp;amp; Letras” section of Chile&amp;rsquo;s leading newspaper El Mercurio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLARICE LISPECTOR: Katrina Dodson at Green Apple Books!</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/clarice-lispector-katrina-dodson-at-green-apple-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 14:41:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/clarice-lispector-katrina-dodson-at-green-apple-books/</guid>
      <description>Translator Katrina Dodson will be joined by readers to celebrate the launch of her translation of The Complete Stories of Clarice Lispector. With readings from The Complete Stories by:
Stephen Beachy Norma Cole Anisse Gross Micheline Aharonian Marcom Namwali Serpell</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Keene &amp; Paolo Javier at The Brooklyn Rail</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/john-keene-paolo-javier-at-the-brooklyn-rail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 19:53:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/john-keene-paolo-javier-at-the-brooklyn-rail/</guid>
      <description>Please join us for a poetry reading by our own John Keene, together with Paolo Javier, hosted by The Brooklyn Rail. 253 36th Street, Third Floor, Ste C304, Brooklyn.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/NMqstjYvghWu17v1gSH6dtBx-0XLSSF8tVZToCO7ZJMcANU5lmsOhk6f11g0KV4hLqYi3QVAqOd7u7QyrIYenO8Mgt0e=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1439495767536/counternarratives.jpeg) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homero Aridjis at the National Book Festival</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/homero-aridjis-at-the-national-book-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 19:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/homero-aridjis-at-the-national-book-festival/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/_mM7SrY_zMa_-Qh3Wjrds44-Oe4B6ETOoSr9_r16NbwOSYCNWIQ1cwYJnEcSHxP4epMd6AdTk2G9K8HKC9TzO-Nt7gD8=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1438803101763/homero_aridjis_163x216..jpg) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLARICE LISPECTOR: Porochista Khakpour &amp; Benjamin Moser at WORD Brooklyn </title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/clarice-lispector-porochista-khakpour-benjamin-moser-at-word-brooklyn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 16:21:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/clarice-lispector-porochista-khakpour-benjamin-moser-at-word-brooklyn/</guid>
      <description>Volume 1 Brooklyn and New Directions present a celebration of the life and work of Clarice Lispector with Benjamin Moser and Porochista Khakpour at WORD Bookstore in Brooklyn.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/Wbdr2a7MLZANeOIjuUqZSCgNx8fBS3rLf3Jd2JUE7YkOeq9kbtfXKAWfdMP9XW-aEhzCfzHoo42NMLTERovRgbujnqA2=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1438791261937/CL_pc01env02_foto014.jpg) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLARICE LISPECTOR: Anderson Tepper &amp; Benjamin Moser at Book Culture</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/clarice-lispector-anderson-tepper-benjamin-moser-at-book-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 16:53:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/clarice-lispector-anderson-tepper-benjamin-moser-at-book-culture/</guid>
      <description>Please join us for a celebration of Clarice Lispector with Anderson Tepper and Benjamin Moser at Book Culture.
Read Anderson Tepper on Clarice Lispector in Tin House and Tablet.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/1yawejKuwutpq12yiENfPe655r2HcMhw0VeO-mUXT8EeB5yVzrKrben20N0dQKvXZZa0_F9Hh0bs0gaA9KS6NJB8Jcm6=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1439399020867/Screen%20Shot%202015-08-12%20at%201.02.40%20PM.png) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FANTASY READING SERIES: Forrest Gander &amp; John Keene at Bowery Poetry</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/fantasy-reading-series-forrest-gander-john-keene-at-bowery-poetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 15:38:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/fantasy-reading-series-forrest-gander-john-keene-at-bowery-poetry/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/SOfmZ5klT_RYNpzrrA29vDjnSCfSE2icXVWoXpR8hnMnTwkzfxNnw4vBCYXBU8EwtSVMCA8gsnErIiVIhJLX1fzVw0R3rA=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1440000997040/Screen%20Shot%202015-08-19%20at%2012.15.39%20PM.png) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>László Krasznahorkai in English – George Szirtes in conversation with Rosie Goldsmith</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/l-szl--krasznahorkai-in-english-george-szirtes-in-conversation-with-rosie-goldsmith/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 17:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/l-szl--krasznahorkai-in-english-george-szirtes-in-conversation-with-rosie-goldsmith/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/HqgSzXzTwVVYH34OtTrjGCiMeSPWaHGC4CiddsFJ1M6vhZHLQkdh1OFszh2FWRl5tiMOo-Z9MRhaweWrxAVxyXi_yno=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1438275772253/11755155_1094968847198777_3803086040170573924_n.jpg) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anne Carson&#39;s Bakkhai by Euripedes at the Almeida Theatre</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/anne-carsons-bakkhai-by-euripedes-at-the-almeida-theatre/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 16:58:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/anne-carsons-bakkhai-by-euripedes-at-the-almeida-theatre/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLARICE LISPECTOR: Two Voices Salon with Katrina Dodson &amp; Scott Esposito</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/clarice-lispector-two-voices-salon-with-katrina-dodson-scott-esposito/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 14:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/clarice-lispector-two-voices-salon-with-katrina-dodson-scott-esposito/</guid>
      <description>For Two Voices Salon&amp;rsquo;s first salon of the 2015-16 season Katrina Dodson discusses her translation of The Complete Stories of Clarice Lispector.
Beginning with Lispector’s adolescence and ending just before her death, these 85 stories show a singular literary intelligence developing throughout an entire lifetime.
Please note: we will be holding this at the Book Club of California (not the Two Lines Press offices, as we usually do). Don’t worry, it’s just a couple of blocks from the Two Lines Press offices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Brooklyn Small Press Flea</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/the-brooklyn-small-press-flea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 16:47:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/the-brooklyn-small-press-flea/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/BB7U1G9IdY4wNS-ApbDLI4ktewKN0ZenysDmNFkAiGVVTWmoV9y-avyhDtLv95GmgVDx6Sb2aQajjOO8fmHZsqq-3EhBLA=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1437756322279/11666021_10153250574989193_3483988142472992462_n.jpg%3Foh%3Da81d60ef230ec3a2c50a146e4c9222e9%26oe%3D56184535) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publisher, Poet, Pittsburgher: A Celebration of James Laughlin</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/publisher-poet-pittsburgher-a-celebration-of-james-laughlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 14:35:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/publisher-poet-pittsburgher-a-celebration-of-james-laughlin/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/m-sLCE8P9cTT70krAoXtak30zmfqnS73Gvw3QanNTWzblrJzRxnwp2DWZJ6aPerVrTH_cdjI2PK0sFtg1U2YbJyGaeY=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1437575536833/James-Laughlin-Featured.jpg) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLARICE LISPECTOR: Paula Cooper Gallery &amp; 192 Books </title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/clarice-lispector-paula-cooper-gallery-192-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 14:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/clarice-lispector-paula-cooper-gallery-192-books/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antigone at University Musical Society</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/antigone-at-university-musical-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 16:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/antigone-at-university-musical-society/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/9Az7XhQtC5rZn3GySzrChP103nu64d5vS1AaBFctDmnhjGrWXnwZFtBhudfshbAT0k7elPz588j-YwvAIGDbDcKbQzND=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1436890255760/Antigonik) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antigone at The Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/antigone-at-the-kennedy-center-for-the-performing-arts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 16:02:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/antigone-at-the-kennedy-center-for-the-performing-arts/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/coBuZ4RA2p0lcbLAn0blbeCmkb5xYnFbR4hNTrpORD1Fps25MPMPqBABn-cHEo0fZzKsCZKIXr5OO_9h5gJvxAYFHhQ=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1442329523804/32384-2015NWF-Image_Suites-Antigone-613X463.png) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antigone at Carolina Performing Arts</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/antigone-at-carolina-performing-arts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 15:48:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/antigone-at-carolina-performing-arts/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/2XMNaRCW8Wkkh9wVAG6S8d-HGL9wcuHU8M0CK_emoD5Z79xi0Ev06XH4PMFrkKWMgT6zEzBCytHhjoDf8BO7XKkrMEcoPw=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1436888544312/Antigonik) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antigone at BAM</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/antigone-at-bam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 18:29:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/antigone-at-bam/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/N9hu7V1EHoAIqzZfTStrzsewV5OenjXg-_rOAUr-KXyWJc-hqE8ZNMuYM_TcV8Sner5dV140GMr2CWejbS7qILfywzAE=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1436293724385/r0RinU0MerlscW3Oeq7ekwZHt5fFbXbwud34iTrCMTm6tkfd3iv9YUHPpGl7gOGtdXzJZq8x8j9bfJCs5ooJHbGCgRBE%3Ds700) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club Discussion of An Episode in the Life of a Lanscape Painter</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/book-club-discussion-of-an-episode-in-the-life-of-a-lanscape-painter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 18:14:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/book-club-discussion-of-an-episode-in-the-life-of-a-lanscape-painter/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/Rpaw0tGOcxkJ8nNq-mbSh4iDOXPgaV2hRjqeilWn5NJgUm9zHpBfYR5d8BQk5CB4ZKHRMVlGk5kdZMHtNsVi1cGvBg_Hnw=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1436292696433/An_Episode_In_The_Life_Of_A_Landscape_Painter.jpg) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Susan Bernofsky &amp; Jay Ponteri at Mother Foucault&#39;s Bookshop</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/susan-bernofsky-jay-ponteri-at-mother-foucaults-bookshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 17:53:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/susan-bernofsky-jay-ponteri-at-mother-foucaults-bookshop/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/NQaWddv3YV0PN5F6IoLS5TKlyUSSU-YxHD-NcWeYPoMeLm7UZAk0JZ0QaJCgKTYjKSj0_aSSVhrzkx32EFOY04upDkk=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1436290842996/bernofsky_susan.jpg) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Keene presents COUNTERNARRATIVES</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/john-keene-presents-counternarratives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 21:06:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/john-keene-presents-counternarratives/</guid>
      <description>John Keene reads from his new book Counternarratives followed by Q &amp;amp; A with bookseller Zach Barocas.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/TfZqkYzy2Uh6ln906KfvMZx4VjgCzHFVnpVT1VCEPqFnlfUYu8UB_bmB0MUekdazRThgReLWzsd43JPndcaCJldLCkU=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1432242234799/John%20Keene_select_9504.jpg) Credit: Nina Subin  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Keene &amp; Christine Smallwood at McNally Jackson</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/john-keene-christine-smallwood-at-mcnally-jackson/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 19:57:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/john-keene-christine-smallwood-at-mcnally-jackson/</guid>
      <description> John Keene and Christine Smallwood in conversation at McNally Jackson.
&amp;ldquo;Counternarratives is an extraordinary work of literature. John Keene is a dense, intricate, and magnificent writer.&amp;rdquo; (Christine Smallwood, Harper&amp;rsquo;s)
Counternarratives out May 21, 2015 [![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/WkSJqNXCe1aovM0ajmMAuMLEaZtavwFftAdhpJqtV93cDJT73lXptq1-oTigxFvghfZRxLYS2dJK6iGohHmw9JIN6EA=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1432237114948/Counternarratives_jacket.jpg) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Keene &amp; Jeffery Renard Allen at Community Bookstore</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/john-keene-jeffery-renard-allen-at-community-bookstore/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 18:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/john-keene-jeffery-renard-allen-at-community-bookstore/</guid>
      <description>John Keene discusses his new book, Counternarratives, with author Jeffery Renard Allen.
&amp;ldquo;Only a few, John Keene among them, in our age, authentically test the physics of fiction as both provocation and mastery. Continuing what reads like the story collection as freedom project, in Counternarratives, Keene opens swaths of history for readers to more than imagine but to manifest and live in the passionate language of conjure and ritual.&amp;rdquo; —Major Jackson</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anne Carson Reading at Portland&#39;s Poetry Downtown</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/anne-carson-reading-at-portlands-poetry-downtown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 15:38:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/anne-carson-reading-at-portlands-poetry-downtown/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/itkKVyEpcRZ3UjpzsRelrM2IC23StB9HCPOx2bzfR19oyU89GePOAXQx1FT4DbJzBBOLo2gnleRiFGzd2h3Sjshur8Q=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1430926682408/annecarson.jpg) Anne Carson is to read at the intimate Winningstad Theatre as part of the Portland Literary Arts&amp;rsquo;s Poetry Downtown series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who We Talk about When We Talk about Translation: Women’s Voices</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/who-we-talk-about-when-we-talk-about-translation-womens-voices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 15:12:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/who-we-talk-about-when-we-talk-about-translation-womens-voices/</guid>
      <description>A panel of experts—writers, translators, editors—will consider the gender bias in literary translations published in the United States. With: Susan Bernofsky, Jen Fitzgerald, Rob Spillman, Véronique Tadjo. This event is free, but reservations are required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Horacio Castellanos Moya and Katherine Silver at Center for the Art of Translation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/horacio-castellanos-moya-and-katherine-silver-at-center-for-the-art-of-translation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 15:03:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/horacio-castellanos-moya-and-katherine-silver-at-center-for-the-art-of-translation/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/DUTNobpV7j-_AoHSszopi-s1x-eXJhgXetmdSMGeM0Ils1rmSafh4oRK66QaEB2jVqIFwPgN7DCQGVHpI3SOGEyPW9N7yg=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1430923803517/moya.jpg) The Center for the Art of Translation welcomes Horacio Castellanos Moya and his translator Katherine Silver to San Francisco to discuss Castellanos Moya&amp;rsquo;s work, including his latest book, The Dream of My Return, which Charles Finch of The New York Times Book Review called &amp;ldquo;easily his best to appear in English so far.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> A Bernadette Mayer Festival </title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/a-bernadette-mayer-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 14:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/a-bernadette-mayer-festival/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/xD0yuTEBsUK3yBoPMBkKHnd67TROtL5A0cItvJAXRNc6TgPYAWpjQr_xm5MGcegrvwNyjIgSoPzqnDPiQYy9Td2cGPMkwg=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1430861930662/Screen%20Shot%202015-05-05%20at%2010.33.42%20AM.png) A night of readings in celebration of the publication Eating the Colors of a Lineup of Words: The First Books of Bernadette Mayer (Station Hill Press, 2015). Readers include Anne Waldman, Barbara Epler, Brenda Coutlas, Lee Ann Brown, Laynie Brown, Sam Truitt, Michael Ruby, Phil Good, Lewis Warsh, Peter Gizzi– and, of course, Bernadette Mayer. A screening of &amp;ldquo;Memory&amp;rdquo; (partial) will also be included.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pen World Voices: Prayer and Meditation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/pen-world-voices-prayer-and-meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 20:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/pen-world-voices-prayer-and-meditation/</guid>
      <description>A wish, an invocation, an impassioned plea. For this contemplative evening of meditation, the festival had commissioned an esteemed assembly of writers and artists from a wide and artists from a wide range of cultural backgrounds to write their original prayer for our time and read it live on stage.
Featuring: Edwidge Danticat, Yahya Hassan, Bob Holman, Maira Kalman, Sayed Kashua, Yusef Komunyakaa, Rachel Kushner, Atticus Lish, Sharifa Rhodes-Pitts, Brenda Shaughnessy, Colm Tóibín, and Jackie Wang.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xi Chuan and Eliot Weinberger in NYC</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/xi-chuan-and-eliot-weinberger-in-nyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 19:51:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/xi-chuan-and-eliot-weinberger-in-nyc/</guid>
      <description>An evening of reading and discussion with poet Xi Chuan and writer Eliot Weinberger, introduced by their New Directions editor Jeffrey Yang. This event is part of BookExpo America&amp;rsquo;s Global Market Forum Honoring China.
&amp;ldquo;Xi Chuan&amp;rsquo;s surprising poems reach into tight corners of mind and matter, impersonal but intimate, new to be heard but also oddly familiar. An impressive voice—bold and calm.&amp;rdquo; —Gary Snyder
&amp;ldquo;Eliot Weinberger&amp;rsquo;s remarkable use of simultaneity and collage is something that didn&amp;rsquo;t quite exist before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Literchoor Is My Beat: A New Directions Festival (NYC) </title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/literchoor-is-my-beat-a-new-directions-festival-nyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 18:43:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/literchoor-is-my-beat-a-new-directions-festival-nyc/</guid>
      <description>Author Ian MacNiven reads from Literchoor is My Beat: A Life of James Laughlin, Founder of New Directions (FSG)
Reading followed by a roundtable discussion about New Directions past and present, featuring Ian MacNiven, New Directions President Barbara Epler, and former New Directions President Peggy Fox. Moderated by Karen Schoemer.
Pop-up book shop featuring current and classic New Directions titles at Time Space Limited, Hudson, NY.
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/PTMKzf63vwbRIRIASjoBmYZXy94RnDEGppnl5dXHiAt2kPLzZKYGd4NgkIv2XVD0dguBCvE65kG-Jk2kgZ5zG1PdD8FQ=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1429900613737/JLPortraits_063%20copy.jpg) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harm___Trangressions</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/harm___trangressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 16:19:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/harm___trangressions/</guid>
      <description>Unnameable Books in Brooklyn is celebrating the release of the new ND Poetry Pamphlet Hospital Series by Amelia Rosselli, translated by Deborah Woodard, Roberta Antognini, and Giuseppe Leporace.
Join translators and poets Deborah Woodard, Yvette Siegert, Montana Ray, and Caitie Moore for an evening of readings and discussion!
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/LQU9aBVaRu0QybRLtj_rnVooGfC79mXfvKUbKqYqn0QHnbUFSHps4w1YxY57LnIm6-2eBjRcC6SZjNmCfpAxsyvCQPW8=s600)](/webhook-uploads/1429633142320/Hospital_series.jpg) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPAZI METRICI: An Evening for Amelia Rosselli</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/spazi-metrici-an-evening-for-amelia-rosselli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 17:51:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/spazi-metrici-an-evening-for-amelia-rosselli/</guid>
      <description>Amelia Rosselli  On occasion of the release of Hospital Series, translated by Roberta Antognini, Giuseppe Leporace, and Deborah Woodard, Centro Primo Levi and ND present an evening of conversation and a video homage to the poet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Norman Manea at Art of the Real </title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/norman-manea-at-art-of-the-real/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/norman-manea-at-art-of-the-real/</guid>
      <description>Le Beau Danger will premiere this year at Film Society Lincoln Center&amp;rsquo;s festival, Art of the Real. A mesmerizing, formally inventive portrait of the Romanian writer Norman Manea, Le Beau Danger is a sensitive meditation on the experience of exile
[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/2H5B_8Jz1r74uxwkuIyAoOonfnb2S_lBVrHILHbCt5hA_WQpQhlWYsewf-f9jGP0PvlnWEtjuUZIhUm84sHq0JWiBlIN=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1429193501287/20148213_2_IMG_FIX_700x700.jpg) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenny Erpenbeck Reading at Princeton</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/jenny-erpenbeck-reading-at-princeton/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 15:41:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/jenny-erpenbeck-reading-at-princeton/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/KHKvshrSMcUhtMB-daG2hojbCE8yyhv_SUt8wUEnrNPOC2hrYW6I4rk3nDXJ4a_RfP1YN0NiTvWfE8CJYTlrBQataivTbQ=s1200)](/webhook-uploads/1429305590789/web_Jenny_Erpenbeck__c__Katharina_Behling.jpg) Jenny Erpenbeck will read from her new novel, The End of Days translated by Susan Bernofsky, at Labyrinth Books Princeton.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYC/CUNY Chapbook Festival 2015</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/nyccuny-chapbook-festival-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 21:46:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/nyccuny-chapbook-festival-2015/</guid>
      <description>2015 Publishers        Over 60 presses share their publications on the concourse level of the CUNY Graduate Center.
The 2015 book fair will take place on Thursday, April 2 from 10AM – 7PM at The Graduate Center, CUNY.
2015 Publishers | Argos Books Art Resource Transfer Belladonna* Collaborative Black Lawrence Press Bloof Books Brooklyn Arts Press Center For Book Arts Deadly Chaps Press DoubleCross Press Fact-Simile Fields Press Flying Object/Factory Hollow Press Folded Word Press Future Tense Greying Ghost Press Harlequin Creature Hidden Clearing Books Ink Press Productions!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rain Taxi Greatest Hits Poetry Reading</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/rain-taxi-greatest-hits-poetry-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 18:31:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/rain-taxi-greatest-hits-poetry-reading/</guid>
      <description>To celebrate its 20th anniversary, Rain Taxi is hosting a night of readings and festivities at AWP 2015. The &amp;ldquo;Greatest Hits&amp;rdquo; portion of the evening will feature readings from Anne Carson, Forrest Gander, Peter Gizzi, Eleni Sikelianos, Cole Swensen, Dara Wier, Pierre Joris, and Nicole Peyrafitte.
Tickets are $10 and available from the Walker Box Office or from Rain Taxi at booth 701 in the AWP book fair.
This final performance of the evening will be followed by a book signing in the lobby and a party from 9-11 in the Cargill Lounge, both free and open to the public!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eliot Weinberger and Teresita Fernández at McNally Jackson</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/eliot-weinberger-and-teresita-fern-ndez-at-mcnally-jackson/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 16:44:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/eliot-weinberger-and-teresita-fern-ndez-at-mcnally-jackson/</guid>
      <description>Golden Scroll by Teresita Fernández  Artist Teresita Fernández and writer Eliot Weinberger will discuss their book #AsAboveSoBelow, published in conjunction with Fernandez&amp;rsquo;s exhibition at MASS MoCA (on view through April 6th).
Introduction by MASS MoCA curator Denise Markonish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWP Mingle </title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/awp-mingle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 15:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/awp-mingle/</guid>
      <description>Joins us for drinks at MacKenzie&amp;rsquo;s Scotch Pub on Thursday night and mingle with New Directions, The Common, Archipelago Books, NYRB Books, Ecotone, and Lookout Books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mei-mei Berssenbrugge at Poetry Project</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/mei-mei-berssenbrugge-at-poetry-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 15:28:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/mei-mei-berssenbrugge-at-poetry-project/</guid>
      <description>Mei-mei reading at The Hole on the Bowery last year. Credit: Jesse Ruddock  Thinking Its Presence: Dorothy Wang with Mei-mei Berssenbrugge and Tan Lin
How and when does racial signification appear in the work of contemporary Asian American writers? A reading and conversation inspired by Dorothy Wang&amp;rsquo;s Thinking Its Presence: Form, Race and Subjectivity in Contemporary Asian American Poetry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>César Aira in Conversation with Rivka Galchen</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/c-sar-aira-in-conversation-with-rivka-galchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 16:41:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/c-sar-aira-in-conversation-with-rivka-galchen/</guid>
      <description>César Aira and Rivka Galchen discuss The Musical Brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live to Write: Cesar Aira &amp; Sergio Chejfec</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/live-to-write-cesar-aira-sergio-chejfec/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 15:13:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/live-to-write-cesar-aira-sergio-chejfec/</guid>
      <description>Ignoring verisimilitude is one of the ways to tear down the division between fiction and reality. César Aira tells stories, sometimes with many realist overtones, but he always upsets the plausible and avoids incidental elements to set his story. The Argentine author will discuss his most recent English publication, The Musical Brain and Other Stories, with Sergio Chejfec, inviting us to that peculiar universe which proves that in life there are events that cannot be explained by Western Rationalism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>César Aira in Conversation with Hari Kunzru</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/c-sar-aira-in-conversation-with-hari-kunzru/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 15:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/c-sar-aira-in-conversation-with-hari-kunzru/</guid>
      <description>The author of at least eighty novels, most of them no more than 96 pages long, César Aira has been called &amp;ldquo;the author who can&amp;rsquo;t be stopped&amp;rdquo; by the New York Review of Books. His new book The Musical Brain &amp;amp; Other Stories is the first collection of his stories to appear in English, and comprises twenty tales about oddballs, freaks, and crazies. Aira gives readers imponderables to ponder and bizarre and seemingly out-of-context plot lines to consider, as well as thoughtful and passionate takes on everyday reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IBERIAN SUITE: Literature Panel: A Song for Iberia: Six Voices of Literary Masters Then and Now</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/iberian-suite-literature-panel-a-song-for-iberia-six-voices-of-literary-masters-then-and-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 15:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/iberian-suite-literature-panel-a-song-for-iberia-six-voices-of-literary-masters-then-and-now/</guid>
      <description>Six writers&amp;ndash;César Aira, Juan Gabriel Vásquez, Dulce María Cardoso, Javier Cercas, Alonso Cueto, and Carmen Boullosa&amp;ndash;join translator Anne McLean to talk about their work amidst echoes from their literary predecessors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Season of Celebration: Thomas Merton at 100 at Columbia University</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/season-of-celebration-thomas-merton-at-100-at-columbia-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 05:16:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/season-of-celebration-thomas-merton-at-100-at-columbia-university/</guid>
      <description>For the centennial of his birth, the Rare Book and Manuscript Library is delighted to present an exhibit on the life and legacy of Thomas Merton, drawn from RBML&amp;rsquo;s very extensive Thomas Merton holdings, from the papers of his teacher and friend, Mark Van Doren, and from those of his friend and official biographer, John Howard Griffin.
Kempner Exhibition Gallery, Rare Book and Manuscript Library</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Directions: The Life and Poetry of James Laughlin</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/new-directions-the-life-and-poetry-of-james-laughlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 02:12:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/new-directions-the-life-and-poetry-of-james-laughlin/</guid>
      <description>Harvard Book Store and the Houghton Library welcome biographer and literary critic IAN S. MACNIVEN and former editor-in-chief of New Directions PETER GLASSGOLD for a panel discussion of their respective works, &amp;ldquo;Literchoor Is My Beat&amp;rdquo;: A Life of James Laughlin,Publisher of New Directions, and The Collected Poems of James Laughlin, moderated by DAVID BARBER.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breakout: Voices from the Inside—A Celebration of PEN American Center&#39;s Prison Writing Program</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/breakout-voices-from-the-insidea-celebration-of-pen-american-centers-prison-writing-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 20:47:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/breakout-voices-from-the-insidea-celebration-of-pen-american-centers-prison-writing-program/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenny Erpenbeck in Conversation with Susan Bernofsky</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/jenny-erpenbeck-in-conversation-with-susan-bernofsky/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 20:48:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/jenny-erpenbeck-in-conversation-with-susan-bernofsky/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PRIMING: Orit Raff exhibition at Julie Saul Gallery</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/priming-orit-raff-exhibition-at-julie-saul-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2014 21:29:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/priming-orit-raff-exhibition-at-julie-saul-gallery/</guid>
      <description>Orit Raff&amp;rsquo;s fifth solo exhibition at JSG features a fully illustrated catalog produced by the Tel Aviv Museum of Art with essays by exhibition curator Nili Goren, Jenny Erpenbeck, and Eva Dias.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poetry Society Readings at McNally Jackson: Susan Howe and Peter Cole</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/poetry-society-readings-at-mcnally-jackson-susan-howe-and-peter-cole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 15:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/poetry-society-readings-at-mcnally-jackson-susan-howe-and-peter-cole/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Under Milk Wood: Listen to the free 92Y livecast</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/under-milk-wood-listen-to-the-free-92y-livecast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2014 17:57:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/under-milk-wood-listen-to-the-free-92y-livecast/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Hinton &amp; Chloe Garcia Roberts at Harvard for Omniglot Seminar: Cosmologies of the Classical</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/david-hinton-amp-chloe-garcia-roberts-at-harvard-for-omniglot-seminar-cosmologies-of-the-classical/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/david-hinton-amp-chloe-garcia-roberts-at-harvard-for-omniglot-seminar-cosmologies-of-the-classical/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NY ART BOOK FAIR: Susan Howe and R. H. Quaytman</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/ny-art-book-fair-susan-howe-and-r-h-quaytman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 19:13:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/ny-art-book-fair-susan-howe-and-r-h-quaytman/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A reading and discussion with László Krasznahorkai</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/a-reading-and-discussion-with-l-szl--krasznahorkai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 14:42:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/a-reading-and-discussion-with-l-szl--krasznahorkai/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lydia Davis and Osama Alomar in conversation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/lydia-davis-and-osama-alomar-in-conversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 14:58:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/lydia-davis-and-osama-alomar-in-conversation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An evening with Jenny Erpenbeck and Susan Bernofsky: TONIGHT</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/an-evening-with-jenny-erpenbeck-and-susan-bernofsky-tonight/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 15:34:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/an-evening-with-jenny-erpenbeck-and-susan-bernofsky-tonight/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Directions Presents: Peter Cole and Ben Lerner at McNally Jackson</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/new-directions-presents-peter-cole-and-ben-lerner-at-mcnally-jackson/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 19:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/new-directions-presents-peter-cole-and-ben-lerner-at-mcnally-jackson/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patti Smith Reading in Brooklyn Bridge Park</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/patti-smith-reading-in-brooklyn-bridge-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2012 14:48:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/patti-smith-reading-in-brooklyn-bridge-park/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>László Krasznahorkai at Housing Works Bookstore Cafe</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/l-szl--krasznahorkai-at-housing-works-bookstore-cafe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 15:11:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/l-szl--krasznahorkai-at-housing-works-bookstore-cafe/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>László Krasznahorkai at City Lights Bookstore in San Francisco</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/l-szl--krasznahorkai-at-city-lights-bookstore-in-san-francisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 15:13:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/event/l-szl--krasznahorkai-at-city-lights-bookstore-in-san-francisco/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>